军火贩
美国  剧情/喜剧/战争
*基于真实事件改编*
*2008年1月1日*
别这样!求求你们!
Please! Please!
对不起 我不会说阿尔巴尼亚语!
I'm sorry, I don't speak Albanian!
别打我!我听不懂你们在说什么!
Stop! I don't understand!
现在听懂了吗?
Do you understand now?
现在指着我头的是一把杰里科941手枪
That's a Jericho 941
pointed at my head
只需要花300美元 你就能在黑市里淘到
You can get one
on the black market for $300
懂了
Yeah
它是一把非常便携好用的武器
It is a very reliable weapon
我叫戴维・佩豪斯
My name is David Packouz
是一个国际军火贩
And I'm an international arms dealer
关于战争你都知道什么?
What do you know about war?
人们会告诉你战争就是爱国民主
They'll tell you it's about
patriotism, democracy
或是某个厌恶我们自由的家伙
or some shit about the other guy
hating our freedom
但是你想知道战争的真正意义吗?
But you want to know
what it's really about?
从这个画面里你看到了什么?
What do you see?
一个来自阿肯色的孩子
A kid from Arkansas
为了实现自己的爱国主义来到前线保家卫国?
doing his patriotic duty
to defend his country?
我看到了一个头盔 一双防火手套
I see a helmet, fire-retardant gloves,
一件防弹衣 以及一把M16突击步枪
body armor, and an M16
我看见了17500美元
I see $17,500
装备一个美国士兵就需要这么多钱
That's what it costs to outfit
one American soldier
有超过两百万个战士
Over two million soldiers
在伊拉克和阿富汗战斗
fought in Iraq and Afghanistan
而这平均会花费美国纳税人每年约45亿美元……
It cost the American taxpayer
$45 billion each year
投入到这些战争当中 而这一部分钱
just to pay the air conditioning bills
才只够抵消空调的费用
for those wars
这才是战争的真正意义
And that's what war is really about
战争就是经济
War is an economy
如果有人告诉你战争不是这样
Anybody who tells you otherwise
那要么他是个蠢货 要么他正参与其中
is either in on it or stupid
但我当时还没认清这一点
But I didn't know that yet
很早以前我几乎什么都不知道
Back then, I didn't know anything
*2005年 迈阿密沙滩*
你不能在这里停车
You can't park here
嘿 伙计 2150号 有我的客户叫肖尔先生
Hey, man I just got
a client at 2150, Mr Shore
但是我来早了
I'm a few minutes early
是吗?但这里是封闭式社区
Yeah? It's a gated community
所以你还是不能在这里停车
You still can't park here
大麻在这里也是禁止的
You probably shouldn't
smoke that here, either
好吧 多谢提醒
Okay Thanks
关于我现阶段的生活是如何影响故事走向的
There's a lot I could say
about this period in my life
我可以说上三天三夜
that would give context to this stow
我可以谈我是如何……
I could tell you how
只上完一个学期就从大学辍学的
I dropped out of college
after one semester
左臀的肌肉感觉怎么样? - 还是很酸痛
- How's that left quad doing?
- It's still sore
我是如何和父母闹翻的
Had a falling out with my parents
我是如何辗转6份工作或自己辞职或被炒鱿鱼的
How I either quit or got fired
from six different jobs
就是这里 - 好的 放松
- That's it
- All right There we go
但现在回想起来
But looking back
我觉得最重要的事是
I think the most important
thing to understand is
我当时非常迷茫
I was completely lost
抱歉 毯子自己掉下去了
Sorry It fell
没关系 加里
That's okay, Gary
我当时22岁
I was 22 years old
专帮迈阿密海滩附近的富豪按摩 每小时赚75块
massaging rich dudes in Miami Beach
for 75 bucks an hour
但我受够了
But I'd had enough
是时候做出改变了
It was time to change shit up
而我有个好主意
And I had a big idea
*要学会发现机遇 才能赚钱*
我的计划就是把高质量的床单批发给……
My plan was to sell
quality bed sheets wholesale
南佛罗里达的所有养老院
to all the retirement homes
in South Florida
这里有上百家养老院
And there were hundreds of them
手感真轻柔 - 那肯定的
- It feels really soft
- It should
这是用的埃及棉 400纱支数
It's Egyptian cotton, 400 thread count
它的品质在家用上 已经算是上乘了
I mean, it's pretty much top of the line
for institutional use
我很纠结 这看起来挺贵的
I don't know It seems excessive
每一床才29美元 一点都不贵
Well, at $29 per unit,
it's far from excessive
戴维 你知道希尔戴尔里住的老人平均年龄吗?
David, do you know the average age
of a resident here at Hilldale?
额 不知道
Um, no, I don't
82岁 - 哇
- Eighty-two years old
- Wow
你有见过82岁老人的皮肤吗?
Have you ever seen the skin
on an 82-year-old man?
你有触摸过吗?
Have you ever felt it?
事实上 我摸过 我之前是一名按摩理疗师
Yeah Actually,
I'm a certified massage therapist
我很多的客户都是上了点年纪的
and a lot of my clients are elderly
那你就应该知道
Then you should know
如果给他们用这些床单
These sheets,
感觉就好比用开士米羊绒裹住一只蜥蜴
it would be like wrapping
a lizard in cashmere
你会这么做吗?
Would you do that?
你会把羊绒拿给蜥蜴用吗?
Would you wrap a lizard in cashmere?
我想不会
I guess not
那你凭什么指望我会?
Then why would you expect me to?
那是我侄子
- My nephew
他唱得很好 对吧?
He's good, right?
我把所有的积蓄都用来买了这65床高级床单
I'd sunk my entire life savings
into 65 cases of premium bed sheets
但我忽视了一个最残忍的事实
but I overlooked one crucial factor
根本就没人关心老年人过得怎么样
No one really cares about old people
你为什么不把它们退回去?
Why don't you just sell them back?
退不了 我是批发的
It doesn't work like that
I bought them in bulk
我完蛋了
I'm so fucked
你没完蛋
You're not fucked
皮特才完蛋了
Pete's fucked
他都死透了
He's dead
我的天那 是埃佛隆吗?
Holy shit Is that Efraim?
是的
Yeah
我以为他还在洛杉矶
I thought he was still in LA
我也是
Me too
他是个很好的朋友 - 谢谢
- He was a great friend
- Thank you
他看起来真有钱
He looks so tan
埃佛隆・迪乌利是我的发小
Efraim Diveroli
was my best friend growing up
但自从他10年级搬去
But I hadn't seen him
since he was shipped off
和他叔叔住之后 我就再也没见过他
to live with his uncle in 10th grade
我想我们的父母一定都想尽办法让我俩离得越远越好
I think our parents wanted to keep us
as far apart as possible
生命之书中是没有目录的
There is no table of contents
in the Book of Life
我们不知道现在所处的位置 是新篇章的开头还是结尾
We don't know if we're at the beginning
of a new chapter, or the end of a story
所以每当有新的一页翻开时
Which is why we must be grateful
我们要心存感激
every time the page turns
你回来就是为了参加葬礼?
Did you come back just for this?
当然不是!我根本就不认识什么皮特
Fuck no! I barely knew Pete
我是来找你的
I was hoping to see you here
知道你妈连你的电话号码都不给我吗?
You know your mom
wouldn't give me your number?
怎么 你有打去家里找我?
What, did you call my house?
没有 我当时正在操她
No, I was fucking her
她还是很恨我 对吗?
She still hates me, huh?
没错 是这样的
Yeah, most likely
我很想你 兄弟
I missed you, bro
我也是
Yeah, me too
我们去兜兜风吧
Let's go for a ride
额
Uh
不行 我4点钟有一个客户
I can't I got a client at 4:00
管他娘的 给我取消了
Fuck that shit Cancel it
你的好兄弟回来了
Your boy's back in town
来嘛!
Come on!
你怎么不在洛杉矶待着了 伙计?
So, what happened with LA, man?
为什么回来?
Why did you move back?
你知道我一直在我叔叔手下工作 对吧?
Oh, you know I was working
for my uncle, right?
对 我听说你们好像是枪贩什么的
Yeah, I heard that you were, like,
a gun dealer or something
差不多吧
Pretty much I mean,
我们现在警方拍卖会上
we'd buy seized weapons at police auctions
and resell them on the Internet
真不错
Cool
之前是挺不错的 直到我发现我叔叔从我这儿克扣了7万块
It was cool until my uncle
scumbagged me over 70 grand
天啊 7万?
Holy shit Seventy grand?
差不多吧 但去他妈的 我还是赚了不少钱
Whatever Fuck him
I made a bunch of money
所以决定回迈阿密自己干
I decided I'd come back to Miami,
start up my own shop
这样啊
Cool
我们要找的那个人住哪儿啊?
Yo, where's this guy live?
还有大概5分钟就到 你赶时间吗?
It's, like, five more minutes
You got somewhere you gotta be?
不
No
好的 我有点不好判断到底哪种情况更糟
All right So, I can't figure out
which is worse
是你向养老院兜售床单
The fact that you sell
bed sheets to old age homes
还是你给人打手枪赚钱
or that you jerk guys off for money
再提醒你一次 我是一名有执照的按摩理疗师好吗?
For the record,
I'm a licensed massage therapist, okay?
完全合法的工作
Totally legit
好吧 但是到最后那些人还是会高潮的 对吧?
Okay But at the end,
the guys have to come, right?
是射在你胸口 还是什么地方?
Like, on your chest or whatever?
知道吗?去你妈的
You know what? Fuck you
去你的伙计
- Fuck you, buddy
兄弟 你还记得我们最后一次一起去买大麻的情景吗?
Bro, do you remember the last time
we went to buy weed together?
当然记得 真是他妈痛苦的经历
Of course I do It was fucking traumatic
没错 但你记得第二天
Yeah, but do you remember the next day,
when we walked into school
然后所有人都知道我们被逮捕的事吗?
and everybody knew that we got arrested?
记得 我们是不法分子
Yeah, we were gangsters, bro
我记得我们好像去了南海滩
We thought we ran South Beach
犹太学校肯定是去了
We did run yeshiva
我们当时真是毫无顾忌
We didn't take shit from anyone
对 我真怀念
Yeah, I miss that
怀念犹太学校?
You miss yeshiva?
不 我是怀念
No, I miss
当时的无所顾忌
not taking shit from anyone
哟!
Yo!
他不在家你是来买大麻的吗?
He out You looking for weed?
不一定 你有好货吗?
Depends You got good shit?
这么说吧 他的货都是从我这里拿的
Put it this way I sell him his shit
那家伙怎么了?
What's up with this nigga, man?
那好 1盎司的货有吗?
Cool Can you do an ounce?
有 绝对足称 一共300
Yeah, no sweat Three bills
300 挺便宜啊
Three hundred I like it
你如果直接找批发商拿货更便宜
You get the better price
when you come direct to the distributor
我想也是
I guess so
好的
All right
所以 她最后还是把门打开了
Yeah, so, she opened the door
我就说,"哟 奇尔 我不想再这样下去了"
And I'm like, "Yo Chill
I ain't about that drama"
你知道我想说什么吗?
You know what I mean?
"我知道你床上还有另外一个男人"
"I know you got
another nigga in the crib"
什么情况?
What's up?
怎么了?
What?
能把货给我了吗?
Can I get the shit?
什么货?
What shit?
我刚拿给你300块钱买大麻
I just gave you $300 for some weed
你们有谁之前见过这个傻叉的吗?
Any of you niggas ever
seen this motherfucker before?
我没见过
I ain't seen shit
伙计 快滚吧
Man, get the fuck out of here
好吧 好吧 我走 - 算你识趣
- All right All right, okay
- Yeah, yeah
这个白人小子真搞笑
This white boy wild
穿个吊带裤
Parachute pants
看着跟杰・雷诺似的
Looking like Jay Leno and shit
搞得跟马上要去教堂一样
Look like he going to church
哟哟 别冲动 别开枪 伙计
Yo, yo, hold up, hold up, man
我去 - 该死!
What the fuck
Shit!
别跑啊!你们这是去哪儿?
Come on! Where's everybody going?
不是要跟我玩儿吗
I thought we were gonna hang out
真是一群混蛋
What a bunch of assholes
刚刚是什么情况?你疯了?
What the fuck was that? Are you crazy?
没关系 伙计
It's cool, bro
我有3级枪支许可证
I have a Class 3 Firearms license
什么? - 快上车
- Huh?
- Come on, get in
这附近还有个有货的
I know another dealer nearby
真是奇怪 虽然我们年纪相仿 但我总是很崇拜埃佛隆
It's weird We were the same age,
but I always looked up to Efraim
当生活给我一记耳光 我就忍着
When life kicked me, I stayed down
但埃佛隆不同 他会打回去
But not Efraim He kicked back
总统先生 我们想感谢您
Mr President, we want to thank you
今天愿意过来加入我们
for visiting us here today
能够为自己的国家效力 我们倍感荣幸
We are honored to be serving our country,
接下来热烈欢迎
and proud to welcome you,
我们的战时总司令
our wartime Commander in Chief
亲爱的
- Hey
- Hey, sweetie
葬礼举行得怎么样?
How was the funeral?
非常棒
It was amazing
天啊 你吸毒了 对吗?
Oh, my God You're so stoned, aren't you?
什么?
- Huh? What?
你刚刚用"很棒"形容一场葬礼
You just described a funeral as "amazing"
什么?不 葬礼真的很让人感伤
What? No The funeral was really sad
所有人都非常伤心
Yeah, everyone was totally bummed out
但是我竟然碰到了我的发小
But I ran into my friend from growing up
我之前跟你提起过埃佛隆・迪乌利 还记得吗?
The guy I told you about Efraim Diveroli?
就是那个害你被捕的人?
The one you got arrested with?
没错 但我们也不只是干这些事
Yeah I mean, we did
some other stuff too, but
总之 他刚搬回了迈阿密
Anyway, he just moved back to Miami
那很棒啊 不是吗?
That's great, right?
是的 我明天要去趟他的办公室
Yeah I'm supposed
to swing by his office tomorrow
我们说好一起吃顿午饭
We're gonna grab lunch
好的 - 你饿了吗?
- Okay
- Are you hungry?
什么? - 我快饿死了
- Hmm?
- I'm so hungry
家里没什么吃的 - 噢
- We don't have much here
- Oh
但是有披萨 - 真的吗?
- I mean, we have pizza
- Really?
还有玉米片 - 家里居然有玉米片?
- And nachos
- We have nachos?
还有冰淇淋
And ice cream
等等你说什么?家里从来不买冰淇淋的
Wait, what? We never have ice cream
你在寻我开心是不是?
You're fucking with me, aren't you?
真是太坏了
- That is so mean
你真好骗
That was so easy
哪位?
Hello?
你好 布斯丁先生 我是戴维・佩豪斯
Hello, Mr Borstein
This is David Packouz
你之前叫我11点给你打电话
You told me to call today at 11:00
那些床单现在都在我车上
I have those bed sheets with me,
and I would love for you to take a look
额 先生 如果你给我一个机会
Uh, sir, if you give me the chance
我敢保证养老院里的老人们
I am confident that your residents
一定会非常喜欢这个新床单的
will appreciate the difference
这笔开销并不在我们的预算范围内 所以我们不感兴趣
It's an expense we can't justify,
and we're just not interested
好吧
Uh-huh
抱歉占用你宝贵的时间
Okay, well, thank you for your time
没错 我是来自陆军司令部
Yeah, this is contract specialist
皮卡丁尼的林德赛・麦克
Lindsey Michaels
from Army Command, Picatinny
没错
That's right
我之前有请求支援一些249式突击枪送往巴士拉
Yeah, I sent out a solicitation
for some 249s for Basra
但好像我们把你们下达的文件弄丢了
and we seem to have
misplaced your paperwork
太好了 所以麻烦你尽快把那些编号重新用邮件发给我
Great So if you can go ahead
and just re-email me those numbers
这样吧 我又想了一下
Actually, you know what?
On second thought,
我们必须马上对那些建议请求书进行选择
we're about to make
a decision on those RFPs
所以既然现在我们正好在通话
Why don't you go ahead
and just give me your bid
你为什么不直接把你的出价告诉我呢?
while I got you here on the phone?
好的
Uh-huh
其中包括弹匣吗?
And does that include mags?
好的 没问题 先生
Great Yes, sir
你继续为我们提供武器 那些坏人就交给我们处理
You keep supplying the guns,
we'll keep killing the bad guys
上帝保佑你
God bless you
真是个傻叉 你好吗 兄弟?
What a fucking tool What's up, bro?
你好 伙计 你刚刚在干什么?
Yo, what's up, man?
What was that all about?
我刚刚在假扮军方人员
Oh, that was me
impersonating an army officer
真的?为什么?
Really? What for?
看看我的竞争者们为这份合同怎么出价
To find out what my competitor's
bidding on a contract
我脑子好使着呢
It's fucking genius
你不是说你只是在网上
I thought that you said you sold,
卖查封的武器给那些手枪爱好者吗
like, seized weapons
to gun nuts on the Internet
现在不是了
Not anymore
现在我只跟一个人做生意
Now I only sell to one gun nut
是吗?是谁?
Oh, yeah? Which one?
牛逼轰轰的美国军队
The US Military, motherfucker
想爽一发吗?
Wanna do a bong hit?
爽吧?
Pretty sick, huh?
所以你现在是卖枪给国防部了?
So what, you sell these things
to the Pentagon?
不仅仅是枪 各种东西我都卖
I sell all kinds of shit to the Pentagon
枪啊 子弹啊 防弹衣什么的
Guns, bullets, body armor
上个星期我卖了400套
Last week, I shipped 400 gas masks
to American Special Forces in Iraq
不是吧
No shit
你干这一行多久了?
How long you been doing this for?
两三个月吧
Two, three months
很赚钱吗?
And you make good money?
噢!伙计
Oh! Fuck, man
这么说吧仅仅过去8周我就赚了20多万了
Put it this way
I did over 200K in the past eight weeks
我之所以告诉你 是因为你是我兄弟
And I'm only telling you that
because you're my boy
我不是在吹牛
I'm not bragging
我操
Holy shit
来看看这个
Yeah Check this out
这个网站是联邦商业机遇网
Fed Biz Opps stands for
Federal Business Opportunities
好比是易贝网 但专卖战争用品
Think eBay, but for war
坦克也能在上面卖? - 伙计 这上面什么都买得到
- They buy tanks on here?
- Bro, they buy everything on here
真是太疯狂了
It was crazy
政府有一个公开的网站
The government had a public website
这上面包含了最近正在投标的每一条军方合同
containing every military contract
currently up for bidding
我总是直接跳过大单子 去寻找那些
But I skip the big ticket items,
and look for the small-ball shit
国防承包商大头不要的小生意
that giant defense contractors ignore
所以人都在争抢同一块派
Everybody's fighting over the same pie
而他们很容易忽视掉旁边的面包屑
But they're ignoring the crumbs
而我就像老鼠一样 专挑这些面包屑下手
I live on crumbs, like a rat
而当这块派就是五角大楼时
And when you're dealing with the Pentagon,
crumbs are worth millions
这样的买卖似乎是从不间断的
These listings
seemed to go on forever
据埃佛隆所言 事实也确实是这样的
And according to Efraim, they did
谢谢你 伙计
- Thanks, man
但是我不明白
So, I don't get it
明明就有一个很完善的国防市场
If there's an entire defense industry,
为什么国防部会愿意在你们这里买东西?
why would the Pentagon
want to buy anything from you?
不是愿不愿意的问题 是他们必须这么做
They don't want to, they have to
还记得少年棒球联合会吗?
Remember Little League?
在赛季末的时候 他们总会颁发一座最有价值球员奖
How, at the end of the season,
they'd give out that big MVP trophy
而有一个小孩总是赢?
and that one kid would always win it?
记得 伊万・塔尔沃特
Yeah, Evan Talbot
没错 但在这之后的某一年有人的妈妈开始抱怨了 记得吗?
Right But then, one year,
somebody's mom complained?
所以他们开始给每个人都颁发一座小奖杯 借此安慰他们?
Then they had to give everybody
a little trophy so they wouldn't feel bad?
就连那个又肥又傻的小孩罗比・弗里德曼都有一个
Even that fat retarded kid,
Robbie Friedman, got one
这就跟现在的情况很像
That's kind of like what's happening here
我还是搞不懂 伙计
I'm still confused, man
国防部在重建伊拉克军队的时候碰到了大麻烦
The Pentagon fucked up
when they were rebuilding the Iraqi Army
他们把所有空标合同 都集中给切尼兄弟 但他们后来被抓
They gave all these no-bid contracts
to Cheney's boys, and they got caught
所以在这之后 布什发起了这种平等竞争的倡议
So Bush started this initiative
to level the playing field
让五角大楼的每一笔花销 每一支枪 每一个炸弹
and now every Pentagon purchase,
every gun, every grenade,
每一发子弹都能由小供货商进行投标 进而供货
every bullet, gets offered to
small businesses for bidding
当然大单子仍然由那些大供货商垄断
And sure, the big dogs
still get the big trophies
但国防部同时也会准备一些小的奖杯
But the Pentagon's
got to give little trophies
安慰全世界的罗比・弗里德曼
to all the Robbie Friedmans of the world
也就是说你就是那个又肥又傻的小屁孩
So, basically, you're a fat retarded kid
兄弟 我是最肥也是最智障的那个
Bro, I'm the fattest and most retarded
根据今天的演讲
In a speech today,
布什总统否定了之前的报道
President Bush said that
contrary to reports
说他并没有打算进攻伊拉克
he has no plans to attack Iran
总统说,"真是可笑"
The President said, "That's ridiculous
"我们在进攻伊拉克的时候根本连计划都没有"
"We didn't even have plans
when we attacked Iraq"
戴维
David
怎么了?
Yeah?
还记得几周前 从我妈家回来时 我们在车上干的事吗?
Remember a few weeks ago, in the car
on the way home from my mom's house?
恩 我记得
Yes Yes, I do
我怀孕了
Well, this happened
你他妈怎么养得起小孩?
How the fuck
are you going to feed a baby?
你考虑过这个问题吗?
Have you even thought about this?
你打算怎么办?
What are you going to do?
余生都用来给别的男人打手枪?
Jerk men off the rest of your life?
这也是个方法 我就是要给别人打手枪赚钱来养活我孩子
Yeah, that's the plan
I'm gonna feed my kid by jerking men off
抱歉
Sorry
好的 也行啊 至少是你自己的想法
Okay, good Well, at least
you thought it through
这一点都不好笑
It's not funny
伙计我死定了
Dude, lam so fucked
我觉得你应该过来跟着我干
I think you should come work for me
你在说什么啊?
What are you talking about?
我是认真的 我需要助手
Seriously, I need the help
戴维 看着我
David, look at me
布什准备在伊拉克发起战争
Bush opened the floodgates in Iraq
这他妈绝对是赚钱的好机会
It's a fucking gold rush
你能邀请我 我很感谢埃佛隆
That's really nice of you, Efraim
感谢个屁!谁他妈在乎?
Fuck nice! Who cares about nice?
我一直想找个人跟我一起干
I've been looking to bring
somebody on for a while now
但问题是 我谁也信不过
The problem is, I don't trust anyone
但你是我兄弟
But you're my boy
恕我直言 我很反对战争
I mean, no offense,
but I'm against this war
我和伊兹都打算去签署请愿书
Me and Iz are going to rallies
and signing petitions
我知道 伙计我也很反对战争
Yeah, dude, I'm against the war too
我他妈恨死布什了
I fucking hate Bush
但这么做绝对不代表支持战争
But this isn't about being pro-war
战争已经发生了
The war is happening
这么做是为了赚钱
This is about being pro-money
埃佛隆说的越多 我越觉得有道理
The more Efraim talked,
the more it made sense
而且跟我其他的生路相比
Besides, compared to my other prospects,
这次机会绝对不可错失
this was the chance of a lifetime
唯一的问题就是 我该怎么跟伊兹说?
My only issue was, what would I tell Iz?
我觉得这主意棒极了
I think it's a great idea
所以我选择了撒谎
So I lied
你是知道的 我一直很看好这类生意
You know I've always
believed in this business
我告诉她 埃佛隆在政府很有人脉
I told her that Efraim
had great contacts in the government
所以比起把床单卖给
And instead of selling bed sheets
分厘必争的养老院
to penny-pinching retirement homes
把它们卖给财大气粗资金充裕的美国军队
we'd now be selling sheets
to the free-spending,
这看起来是笔好买卖
overfunded US Military
真有头脑
It's genius
我必须对她说谎 伊兹恨死战争了
I had to lie Iz hated the war
她有两个堂兄 就在伊拉克服役
She had two cousins serving in Iraq
她也非常不喜欢占了我们公寓一半、堆积如山的床单
She also hated the mountain of bed sheets
that were taking up half our apartment
之后的6个星期 我接受了军火买卖的速成课
I spent the next six weeks
in a crash course on arms dealing
这是赫斯塔尔556式轻机枪
The Herstal 556 light machine gun
原制造于比利时 但现在很多地方都可以生产
Belgian, but made under license
in lots of places
当涉及到武器的问题 埃佛隆就什么都知道
When it came to this shit,
Efraim knew everything
品质 模型 重量 产地
Makes, models, weights, where it was made
记住在中国的天安门广场 有武器禁运令
Remember, there's been an arms embargo
against China since Tiananmen Square
如果有避开这些风险的方法
And if there was
an angle to be played,
他也知道
he knew about that too
处理武器问题时 你要学会智取
You have to read between
the lines with this stuff
要学会发现机遇 才能赚钱
All the money is made between the lines
我会花一整天的时间翻阅政府网站
I'd spend my entire day
scouring the government's website,
寻找那些被忽视的合同 然后想办法掺一脚
searching for overlooked contracts
that we could squeeze our way into
嘿 我有发现
Hey, I think I got something
嘿 乔治亚 我一会儿再打给你
Hey, Georgia, I gotta call you back
然后到半夜的时候
And then,
in the middle of the night
我们会回到办公室不停地打电话
we'd be back in the office,
working the phones
跟整个东欧的
Forging relationships
武器制造商打好关系
with weapon manufacturers
all over Eastern Europe
不 我是来自AEY的戴维・佩豪斯
No, David Packouz from AEY
我告诉伊兹 我们在跟巴基斯坦的床单供货商电话会议
I told Iz we were doing conference calls
with sheet suppliers in Pakistan
我们这类人被别人称作军火贩
They called guys like us war dogs
就是那种靠战争吃饭的可鄙之人
Bottom feeders who make money off of war
因为我们从来不用自己上战场
without ever stepping foot
on the battlefield
虽然这个词挺贬义的 但我们很喜欢
It was meant to be derogatory,
but we kinda liked it
你他妈个死人渣!
You fucking scumbag piece of shit!
去死吧 混蛋 下地狱去吧!
Drown, motherfucker, drown!
非常好
Very nice
拉尔夫・斯卢茨基是埃佛隆的秘密合伙人
Ralph Slutsky
was Efraim's silent partner
他是本地的一个商人
He was a local businessman
在迈阿密拥有14个干洗店
who owned 14 dry cleaners
all across Miami
为什么没人告诉我机器坏了?
Why didn't anybody tell me
the mister is broken?
拉夫尔投钱资助买卖 但要求25%公司股权作为交换
Ralph put up the money to back the deals
in exchange for 25% of the company
但只是他自己以为有25%
Or at least what he thought was 25%
我们现在做的事是神圣的拉夫尔
We're doing God's work, Ralph
确实
We really are
每个犹太人对以色列都是有所亏欠的
You know, every Jew owes a debt to Israel
在我看来 这种亏欠不能仅靠口头上弥补
In my mind, this is not
a metaphorical debt
拉夫尔被蒙在鼓里
Ralph was under the impression
他一直以为埃佛隆是一个心思缜密的犹太人
that Efraim was an observant Jew
他买卖军火的目的
who only dealt arms as a means
是出于保护以色列免受敌国的侵蚀
to protect Israel from her enemies
说得太棒了
Beautifully said
你有看上个星期五的《妥拉读经》吗?
Did you happen to catch
last Friday's Torah portion?
那是我最爱看的节目 - 我也是
- One of my favorites
- Same here
那次节目让我想起我之前读到过的一个故事
It reminds me so much
of this story I once read
是关于一个旅游到平斯克的男孩的
About a young man traveling to Pinsk
这就是埃佛隆的天才之处
And that was Efraim's genius
他总能从别人身上打探到那个人愿意和哪种人打交道
He would figure out
who someone wanted him to be
然后自己就扮演那个人的角色
and he would become that person
啊!
Ah!
他手下有将近两万人
And he's got, like, 20,000 of them
太好了 你是怎么联系上他的?
Great
Where did you find this guy?
你还记得乌克兰的维克托吗?
You remember Victor in the Ukraine?
记得就是那个买Mk3的家伙?
Yeah, the one with the Mk3s?
没错 他把我介绍给了一家塞浦路斯的公司
Yeah He turned me
on to this company in Cyprus
那个公司的老板是亨利・吉拉尔
It's run by this guy, Henry Girard
亨利・吉拉尔?
Henry Girard?
是的 你认识他?
Yeah, you know him?
你跟亨利・吉拉尔通过话?
You spoke to Henry Girard?
是通过几次怎么了?他是谁?
A couple of times Why? Who is he?
伙计 在过去20年里哪里有战争哪里就有他
Dude, for the last 20 years,
this guy has basically supplied
并且交战双方的武器他都供应
both sides of every conflict
on the planet
他就是个疯子
He's a fucking animal
真的吗?那他为什么给我打电话?
Really? Why is he calling me?
因为他是个疯子
Because he's a fucking animal
小钱大钱都是钱都要赚
It's all money and it all matters
嘿 美女 你要去哪儿?
Hey, mami, where are you going?
找我朋友
I'm trying to find my friends
你想赚点外快吗?
You want to make some money?
你说什么?
Excuse me?
我可以现在就给你1千块
I'll give you $1,000 right now
但我们得直接跳到第3次约会阶段
if we fast forward to our third date
这是什么意思?
What does that even mean?
就是说我们刚刚吃完烛光晚餐
It means we just had a great dinner,
maybe met your friends for some drinks
现在你要和我上车在车上帮我口
and now you're about to blow me in my car
我们能直接跳到这一部分吗?
Can we just get right to that part?
你他妈是谁啊?
Who the fuck are you?
埃佛隆・迪乌利
Efraim Diveroli
那是我最好的朋友戴维
That's my best friend, David
我们是国际军火商
And we're international arms dealers
但这些你应该都知道了
But you already know that
因为这是我们的第3次约会
because we're on our third date
怎么回事? - 没什么伙计
- What's going on?
- Nothing, bro
我正想和我的马子一起离开这里
I'm about to get out of here with my girl
搞什么鬼!
What the fuck, man!
我的天啊
Oh, my God
那个家伙居然动真格的
That guy was not fucking around
是啊 你应该换个马子钓的
Yeah, you probably should have
picked a different girl
胡说 我都快成功了
Fuck that, it almost worked
嘿 你还记得6年级 你和埃里克莫斯考维茨打架那次吗?
Hey, do you remember when you fought
Eric Moscowitz in sixth grade?
记得他当时使出了他的"旋风手臂"
Yeah, he did that windmill thing
with his arms
这就是最诺牡胤 你根本就打不到他
That was the sickest He was unbeatable
你还记得这一招吗?
You remember that shit?
就是这样的
That's it
伙计 如果当时你不来帮我 我就死定了
Dude, he would have killed me
if you didn't jump in
也许吧
Probably Mmm
嘿 我从没说过"谢谢"
Hey, I never said "thank you"
你为我做的所有事
For everything
你也知道最近你帮了我多大的忙
Come on, you know how much
you've helped me out lately
没关系 不要把气氛搞得这么尴尬好吗?
It's cool You don't have to
make it weird, all right?
嘿 我们能点餐了吗?
Hey, can we order some food?
小姐 快点 这等的时间都够我去趟古巴
Mami, come on
I could have gone to Cuba and back
和家人见面再吃几块三明治
Met the family,
grabbed a couple sandwiches
再回来的了
- I'd be done by now
哪位?
Hello?
是的 先生 抱歉 没想到这么晚还能接到您的电话
Yes, sir Sorry, I wasn't expecting
a work call this late
当然没问题 现在是巴格达早上9点
Right, of course
It's 9:00 am in Baghdad
是谁?
Who is it?
这真是个好消息 桑托斯上尉
That's great news, Captain Santos
好的 先生
Yes, sir
我们马上发货
We're going to get right on that
谢谢 再见
Thank you Bye
怎么了?
What?
贝雷塔那一单被我们拿下了
We just got the Beretta deal
别开玩笑了
Get the fuck out of here
我发誓是真的
I swear to God
贝雷塔单子的数额非常巨大
The Beretta deal was massive
是我们之前接过的单子的10倍
It was 10 times bigger
than anything we'd closed so far
我们的生意终于有进展了
This was next level shit
这就是我所设想的那样!
That's what I'm fucking talking about!
赚大钱该死!操!
That's real money, motherfucker! Fuck!
你有意识到做完这笔
Do you realize we're going to make 600K
我们就能赚60万吗?
on this fucking thing?
天啊
Holy shit
戴维 你的30%算下来就是18万
David, your 30% is $180,000
我的苍天老天爷啊!
Holy fucking shit!
那感觉真是太棒了
It was amazing
我只为埃佛隆工作了两个月
I'd been working with Efraim
for two months
赚的钱就比我按一辈子按摩
and was already about to make more money
赚的还要多
than a lifetime of massages
*坦白从来就没有什么好结果*
快听
Listen
那是什么声音?
What is that?
你宝宝的心跳声
- That's your baby's heartbeat
哇
Wow
跳得多快啊 你能相信吗?
Can you believe how fast it is?
是正常的吗? - 完全正常
- Is that normal?
- Totally normal
胎儿的心跳频率比我们的要快很多
Fetuses have a much faster heart rate
than we do
你看啊
Look
你们想知道宝宝的性别吗?
So, you guys want to know the sex?
我们一直拿不定主意
- We keep going back and forth on it
你觉得呢? - 额
- What do you think?
- Um
是工作的电话我必须得接
This is work I have to take it
非常抱歉
I'm so sorry
我是戴维
This is David
我是巴格达的桑托斯上尉
This is Captain Santos in Baghdad
想确认一下我们买的贝雷塔的送货情况
checking on the delivery
status of my Berettas
上尉 很高兴接到你的电话
Captain, good to hear from you
您的货正在路上 一切正常
Yes, we are on target All good
那就好 我还担心
Great I was worried
这些枪是不是直接从意大利运送出来呢
those guns were coming
direct out of Italy
当然 绝对是直接送出来
Absolutely They are, sir
佩豪斯请你告诉我
Packouz, please tell me
你知道上周意大利人通过的法案
you're aware of the legislation
the Italians passed last week
禁止一切运往伊拉克的武器离港
The one banning
all arms shipments to Iraq
我根本不知道他在讲什么
I had no clue
what he was talking about
但这绝对是个大麻烦
But this was a huge fucking problem
贝雷塔是意大利制手枪
Berettas are an Italian gun
通常都是在意大利制造生产的
Made and manufactured in Italy
额
Uh
我当然知道
Of course
最近3天我的电话就没停过
I am I've been on the phone
我一直在做协调和安排
for the last three days,
making other arrangements
那就好 这就是我想听到的回答
Great
That's what I wanted to hear
伊拉克警察部队就全靠你了
Iraqi police force is depending on you
你告诉他们有AEY在 叫他们放心好了
Well, you tell them AEY
has got them covered
非常好 - 谢谢你上尉 我会再打给你的
- Outstanding
- Thanks, Captain Talk soon
没事吧?
Everything okay?
没事 一切都好
Yeah Yeah, everything's fine
怎么了?已经检查完了?
What happened? We done already?
对 你猜怎么着?
Yeah Guess what?
是个女孩
It's a girl
亲爱的
Baby
好吧 至少我没脱靶
Okay At least I hit something
说真的 我们到底应该怎么办?
Seriously, what the fuck
are we going to do?
放轻松 伙计
Relax, bro
我要不要回电给他 然后告诉他实情?
Should I just call him back
and tell him the truth?
坦白从来就没有什么好结果
When does telling the truth
ever help anybody?
埃佛隆 我们不能一直瞒着他
Efraim, we can't dick around with this guy
到最后货物没到 他还是会发现的
and then not deliver
货一定会到的 我已经想到办法了
We're going to deliver
I already figured it out
我们通过约旦运货
We use Jordan
乔丹・戈德法布?
Jordan Goldfarb?
约旦
Jordan
那个国家约旦
Jordan the country
它和伊拉克接壤 并且是美国的同盟国
It shares a border with Iraq
It's a US ally
更重要的是那里没有禁运令
And most importantly, there's no embargo
那好 我们该怎么跟意大利人讲?
Okay, so what do we tell the Italians?
管他妈的!这5千支贝雷塔是要送去约旦的
Fuck them! As far as they're concerned
而这个国家的事 他们管不着
they're sending 5,000 Berettas
to a country they have no issue with
我们只需要确保有人能从约旦
All we have to do is ship the guns
把枪运到巴格达就行了
from Jordan to Baghdad
这就叫智取
It's called circumvention
这么做合法吗?
Is that legal?
反正不违法
It's not illegal
要试试吗?
Want to try?
那场慈善晚会办得怎么样?
How did that charity thing go?
是筹集了5千块 对吧?
It was 5K, right?
目标是定的5千
It was supposed to be a 5K
但我只完成了5分之一
Uh, I finished about 1K of it
所以我要把我拿走的那5分之4还回来
So, I should probably return
four-fifths of the money
安德鲁告诉我
So, Andrew told me
你现在在和埃佛隆合作?
you and Efraim are working together now?
不是吧?
Really?
没错我告诉她你卖床单的事了
Yeah, I told her about the sheet thing
对 埃佛隆在政府有认识的人
Yeah Efraim has some contacts
with the government
所以我们现在就一起干了
So we're just combining forces right now
好吧 只是在他身边你要小心点
Yeah, just Just be careful with him
艾米丽别说了 - 怎么了?
- Emily, don't
- What?
此话怎讲?
How do you mean?
他的表妹丽贝卡是我的一个老朋友
Well, his cousin, Rebecca,
is an old friend of mine
我们以前经常一起去野营
We went to camp together
她告诉我他从她爸爸那儿偷走了7万块钱
And she told me
that he stole $70,000 from her father
哇 真的吗?
Whoa, really?
这就有意思了
That's interesting
我听到的故事版本和这个恰巧相反
I actually heard
it was the other way around
偷钱的人应该是他叔叔 他才是受害者
That his uncle is the one
who stole the money from him
看吧 你就是不听我的
See? You don't know
每个人都有不同的故事版本
Everyone has their own version of a story
不 我非常确信
No, I'm pretty certain
因为这件事 她家里的所有人都不理他了
Their whole family
stopped talking to him over it
哟!你为什么不接电话?
Yo! Why aren't you answering your phone?
嘿 你好吗 伙计?
Hey, what's up, man?
这什么情况?
Fuck is this?
大家 这位就是戴维的生意伙伴 埃佛隆
Everyone, this is David's
business partner, Efraim
嘿 兄弟 - 嘿 兄弟
- Hey, man
伙计 你能到外面来几分钟吗 我有话有跟你讲?
Bro, could I talk to you
outside for a minute?
挺急的 - 当然
- It's urgent
- Yeah, of course
提醒你们一下 我也是他最要好的朋友
And for the record,
I'm also his best friend,
所以你们有什么活动最好也叫上我
so probably should have been
invited to whatever this is
听着 这些都是她的朋友 这也是她举办的晚宴
Look, these are her friends
This is her dinner party
罗斯什么时候成她朋友了?那个犹太佬?
Rosen is her friend now? That Jew fuck?
相信我 你不会想参加的
Trust me, you don't want to be here
就连我都待不下去了 知道吗?
I don't want to be here, all right?
有什么事吗?
Now, what's going on?
约旦的海关把我们的贝雷塔扣下了
Jordanian customs seized our Berettas
什么?怎么了? - 我他妈不知道戴维
- What? Why?
- I don't fucking know, David
我是在他们改变
I dropped out of high school
外交政策以前从高中辍学的
before they covered
international diplomacy
谁打来的? - 该死是桑托斯
- Who's that?
- Fuck, it's Santos
他全都知道了!
He knows!
快接电话 我要听
Pick it up, I want to listen
把把电话接起来 - 我是戴维
- Pick Pick up the fucking phone
- This is David
我听说我的枪被扣在约旦了
Yeah, I just heard
my guns are being held up in Jordan
桑托斯上尉 没错 现在是出了点小小的意外
Captain Santos, yes,
there's been a slight hiccup
它们怎么跑到约旦去了?
What are they even doing in Jordan?
这你不用担心
Not to worry
它们现在在安曼的一个中转站里 非常安全
They're in a hangar in Amman
Totally safe
我和我的团队正在想办法解决这个问题
My team and I are working
on a solution right now
你没有回答我的问题
You didn't answer my question
我的枪怎么跑到约旦去了?
What the fuck are my guns doing in Jordan?
桑托斯上尉 我是埃佛隆・迪乌利
Captain Santos, this is Efraim Diveroli
是AEY的董事
President of AEY, sir
戴维 把现在的情况
David has apprised me of the situation
都告诉我了 我希望我们能讨论出一个备选方案
and we are looking at options as we speak
备选方案?什么备选方案?
Options? What kind of options?
你知道乌鸦TP19式手枪吗?
Well, are you familiar
with the Corvus TP19?
巴西造的破铜烂铁
That's Brazilian and it's shit
合同上写的是贝雷塔 我就要贝雷塔
Contract says Berettas, I want Berettas
长官 我希望你能理解我们一下
Sir, I need you to work
with us a little on this
我就直说了吧
Let me get this straight
我现在身处世界上最艰难的环境 为了你们的自由拼死拼活
I'm in the ass crack of the world,
defending your freedom
还要我理解你们?
And I got to work with you shit bags?
听着 我不知道
Look, I don't know
那些贝雷塔现在是否在安曼
if those Berettas are really in Amman
或者你们只是想尽全力保住自己从中获利
or if you're just trying
to goose your profits
就跟干你们这行的都是些可悲丑陋的人
like every other piece of shit
in your miserable, rat-fuck profession
不管如何 你们都已经影响到我本次任务
Either way, you're endangering my mission
我要取消和你们的合作
I'm shutting you down
我要封杀你们
I'm canceling you for cause
封杀就好比给我们判了死刑
Getting canceled for cause
was a death sentence
那意味着我们别想再赢得任何一个合同
It meant we would never
win another contract
上尉 求你别这样做
Captain, please do not do that
我知道你现在很生气
I know you're upset
但看在大家都是信徒的份上
But from one Christian to another
我妻子和我正面临非常严峻的经济危机
my wife and I are having
serious financial problems
我们的孩子卢卡斯现在在医院接受治疗
Our son, Lucas, is in the hospital
他的医疗费用已经超出了我们的可承受范围
Medical bills are through the roof
如果你这么做 不仅会毁了我还会毁了我整个家庭
If you do this, it'll ruin me
It'll ruin my family
我对天发誓
As God as my witness,
一定会把枪给你送去
- I will get you your guns
喂?
Hello?
真他妈是个混蛋!你能忍吗?
What a fucking piece of shit!
Do you believe this fucking guy?
该死 - 你们在说什么?
- Fuck
- What's going on?
什么枪 戴维?
What guns, David?
你他妈是在逗我吗?
Are you fucking kidding me?
你不是说你们在卖床单吗
You told me you guys
were selling bed sheets
没错 但我也说了我们还卖其他东西的
Yeah, and I also told you
that we're selling other stuff too
我以为你说的是枕头!
I thought you meant pillows!
听着 光靠按摩 我怎么可能养得起孩子
Look, I can't support a kid
by giving massages
明白吗?而且根本就没人愿意买床单
Okay? And nobody
was buying the bed sheets
不 戴维重点是你骗了我
No, David, you lied to me
因为我知道你对于战争的看法
Because I know how you feel about the war
我以为在这一点上我们是同一战线的!
I thought we both felt that way!
我已经怀孕5个月了!
I'm five months pregnant!
但如果连孩子的爸爸我都不能信任的话
And it's a problem
if I can't trust the man
那问题可就大了!
I'm having a baby with!
你当然可以信任我 - 真的吗?
- Of course you can trust me
- Really?
因为5分钟前
Because five minutes ago,
我连你是个军火商都不知道!
I didn't even know
you were an arms dealer!
我不是什么军火商
I'm not an arms dealer
我们的工作是完全合法的
What we do is perfectly legal
我们只是为政府工作相当于中间人
We work for the government
We're middlemen
我们根本不接触武器 甚至连武器的面都见不到
We don't touch the guns,
we don't see the guns
我们连办公室都没出过
We never even leave the office
嘿 抱歉 打扰一下 现在是特殊时期
Hey, sorry to interrupt
It's time sensitive
戴维 你有护照吗?
David, do you have a passport?
怎么了?我有要干嘛?
What? Yeah, why?
我们要去趟约旦 我是说马上就去
We have to go to Jordan Like, ASAP
把烂摊子收拾干净
Straighten this shit out
等会再聊 好吗?
We gotta talk, whatever, okay?
好吧
Yeah
你要坐靠窗还是走道?
Yo, you window or aisle?
不好意思 借过 - 对 我们刚下飞机
- Excuse me, sorry
- Yeah, we just landed
借过 - 大使馆的电话?
Excuse me
The Embassy call?
借过 - 好的 再见
Excuse me Okay, bye
抱歉 我们有急事 - 抱歉 借过
- Sorry, kind of an emergency
- Excuse me Sorry
没事 我插个队 哥是美国人
Don't worry, I have to go first
I'm American
抱歉
I'm sorry
美国大使馆在处理海关的问题上
The American Embassy
offered little to no help
基本提供不了任何的帮助
in dealing with the Ministry of Customs
所以我们决定自己上手
So we took matters into our own hands
他说你们的许可证已经过期了
He says your permit has expired
没有许可证 就不能开飞机把货从约旦运出去
and that you can't fly your crates
out of Jordan without one
这我们知道 所以我们才来找他啊
Yeah, we know That's why we're here
听着 我们听说你在政府有认识的人
Look, we were told that
you know people in the government,
或许你能帮帮我们
that maybe you can help us out
他说要想办理一张新的许可证 需要至少6周的时间
He says it will take six weeks
to get a new permit
这就是问题的关键 我们没那么多时间
Yeah, that's the issue
We don't have six weeks
我们今天就要把枪搞到
We need our guns today
听着 我不想一来就扮演一个美国阔佬的角色
Look, I don't want to come off
as the ugly American here
我也不清楚在你们的文化里有没有什么礼节
And maybe I don't understand
the rituals of your culture
但我感觉这个点
but this feels like the moment
是我应该有所表示的时候了 我说的没错吧?
where we are supposed to offer
him a gift, am I correct?
没错 - 好吧
- You are correct
- All right
1400美元可以吗?
$1,400 US Cool?
可以
Cool, man
早就应该亮票子了
Could have just started with that,
you know, saved all this bullshit
我挺喜欢你的墨镜的
I like your shades
告诉他 我愿意花100块买下他的墨镜
Tell him I'll give him
100 bucks for those shades
快翻译给他听
Tell him in gibberish
没门 这可是短吻鳄牌的
No way Alligator
我知道
Yeah, I know I
应该是"法国鳄鱼"那个标志是一条鳄鱼
It's Lacoste It's actually a crocodile
我就喜欢浮夸的东西 那个很对我胃口
I like fancy shit, that's my thing
快翻译
Tell him
整整3天时间 一点消息都没有
For three days,
we didn't hear anything
想想也是可笑
It was ridiculous
我们的整个生意都要仰仗一个11岁的小翻译
Our entire business was riding on the word
of an 11-year-old translator
混蛋!他欺骗了我们!
Motherfucker! He ripped us off!
现在还不清楚
We don't know that yet
不!我知道糊弄别人是什么感觉
No! I know what it feels like
to fuck somebody
我也知道被人糊弄是什么感觉
I also know what it feels like
to get fucked by somebody
所以我们肯定是被耍了
And we just got fucked
你冷静点
You need to chill out
你要我怎么冷静 戴维?
How am I supposed to chill out, David?
我们现在在一个穆斯林国家 想找个给我口的人都没有!
We're in a Muslim country,
I can't even get a blowjob!
太他妈尴尬了!
It's embarrassing!
这里真是太乱了!操!
It's chaos here! Fuck!
是我
Yeah
现在吗?
Right now?
我们马上下来
We're coming down
是阿拉丁打来的 他们现在在大厅
That was Aladdin They're in the lobby
看吧 我们快下去
See that? Come on
等一下 你们不是在逗我吧?
Hold on Are you fucking kidding me?
有什么问题吗?
What's the problem?
你想把枪找回来 他就帮你要回来了呀
You wanted your guns back,
he got you your guns back
什么?不 我们是想搞一张许可证 把东西用飞机运到伊拉克去
What? No, we said we needed a permit
to fly them to Iraq
没错 但是开车送过去就不需要许可证了
Exactly, but you don't need
a permit to drive them
你想让我们带着枪开车去伊拉克?
You expect us to drive them to Iraq?
为什么不呢?万宝路是整个约旦最会走私的人
Why not? Marlboro is the best
smuggler in all of Jordan
谁 他吗?
Who, this?
他就是整个约旦最利索的走私犯?
This is the best smuggler
in all of Jordan?
是的 他每个月要往返巴格达3、4次呢
Yeah, he drives to Baghdad
three, four times a month
埃佛隆 你想过来说几句吗?
Efraim, you want to weigh in here?
从这里到巴格达有多远?
Yo, how far is it to Baghdad?
你为什么问这个? - 800公里
- Why are you asking him that?
-800 kilometers
他知道自己在干什么?
And he knows what he's doing?
埃佛隆 别这样
Efraim, stop
绝对没问题 - 走吧
- 100% the best
- Come on
就差不多500英里距离 我们明天一早就能到
It's like 500 miles
We'll be there by morning
你真的打算开车去巴格达?
You seriously want to drive to Baghdad?
戴维 我们是搞军火生意的
David, we're gunrunners
真真切切走私一把有什么不好
Let's go run some fucking guns
出发吧
Let's go
快啊
Come on
嘿 讲真的 这安全吗?开车去巴格达?
Hey, seriously, is this safe?
Driving to Baghdad?
非常安全
Yes, very safe
一半一半
50-50
一半一半?你是说有50%的机率活下来 50%会死吗?
50-50? What, like 50% we live, 50% we die?
没错 所以我们才会选择走夜路
Yes That is why we drive through night
这样更安全点
It is much safer
能有多安全?
How much safer?
一半一半
50-50
伙计搞什么!
Bro, what the fuck!
很明显他也不知道一半一半是什么意思
Obviously, he doesn't know
what 50-50 means
我的天啊
Oh, my God
嘿 汽油怎么办?这路还长着呢?
Hey, what about gas though?
It's a long trip, no?
没问题 伊拉克的汽油都是免费的
No problem Petrol free in Iraq
不是吧
No kidding
免费汽油? - 是的
- Free gas?
- Yeah
知道我在说什么了吧?伊利卡屑爆了
See what I'm talking about? Iraq is dope
我打算在那里安个家
I'm thinking about getting a place there
*伊拉克 310公里*
免费汽油
Free gas
真酷
Fucking cool, man
那是什么?
What is that?
怎么了?
What?
你没看到吗?
You don't see that?
什么鬼?
What the fuck?
嘿 你为什么要减速伙计?
Hey, why are you slowing down, man?
没关系 别紧张
It's okay, it's okay
什么没关系?
- What's okay?
喔喔 什么情况 兄弟?
Whoa, whoa What the fuck, bro?
没关系 到边界了
It's okay Border
什么 这里吗?
What, this?
该死
Fuck
天啊 - 把窗户摇下来
- Jesus
- Put down
什么? - 摇窗下来
- Huh?
- Put down
去哪里? - 巴格达
他们是谁?
他们在巴格达做生意 - 什么类型的生意?
运的什么?
喔喔
Whoa, whoa
是香烟
Cigarettes
给你们的
For you
请笑纳
Welcome
*伊拉克 安巴省(伊拉克暴力程度最高的一个省)*
一切感觉就像是在做梦
It was fucking surreal
6个月前我还在迈阿密海滩帮别人按摩
Six months ago,
I was a massage therapist in Miami Beach
而现在我正坐在一辆装满枪支的卡车上
And now, here I was,
driving a truckload of guns
和我初中最好的朋友一起
through the Iraqi desert
穿越伊拉克的沙漠
with my best friend from junior high
*上帝保佑迪克・切尼时期的美国*
万宝路?
Marlboro?
嘿 万宝路?
Hey, Marlboro?
伙计!
Bro!
加油站里面有一具尸体!
There's a dead body in the gas station!
什么情况!
What the fuck!
我们这是在哪儿?万宝路哪儿去了?
Where are we? Where's Marlboro?
你没听见我刚刚说什么吗?
Did you not hear what I just said?
那里面有一具尸体 伙计!
There's a fucking dead body in there, man!
我听到了
Yes, I heard you
别紧张 我们现在在战争中心
All right, we're in a war zone, bro
尸体遍地都是 放松点
There's dead bodies, relax
好了 我要去尿个尿
All right, I gotta take a leak
什么?
What?
小心点
Be careful
没事的 撒尿我还是会的 不是吗?
I'm good, bro
I know how to take a piss, all right?
该死
Shit
操
Fuck
喂? - 嘿
- Hello?
- Hey
嘿 亲爱的 你还好吗?
Hey, babe, is everything okay?
我很好
Yeah
你那里现在是几点?
What time is it there?
早上7点半
It's, uh, 7:30 in the morning
该死 我有吵醒你吗?
Shit, did I wake you?
没事 我在酒店里 正准备去吃早餐
No, I'm just at the hotel
We're about to have some breakfast
听着 我这么说不代表我支持
Listen, I'm not saying I like it,
但我可以理解你为什么这么做
but I get why you're doing this
真的吗?
You do?
这段时间 我一直没有考虑你的感受
This whole time I never thought
about what you must be going through
还有你所面临的一切压力
All the pressure you're under
唯一让我伤心的是你欺骗了我
It's just the lying that kills me
这让我感觉自己很无助
It makes me feel like I'm in this alone
不 你不是一个人
No, you're not in this alone
我想告诉你 不管什么事 你都可以跟我倾诉 戴维
I need you to know
that you can tell me anything, David
我们是搭档 记得吗?
We're partners, remember?
戴维?
David?
我晚点再打给你
Yeah, I gotta call you right back
出什么事了吗? - 没事 一切都很好
- Is everything okay?
- Yeah, everything's fine
只是我现在必须挂电话了 好吗?
I'm just going to call you
right back, okay?
我爱你 再见
I love you Bye
埃佛隆!
- Efraim!
Efraim!
怎么了? - 快看!
- What?
- Look!
万宝路!
- Marlboro!
操!什么情况
- Fuck! What the fuck, bro
该死他们手上有枪!
Holy shit, they have guns, man!
我知道!
I know!
走 快走!快啊
Go, go! Come on
搞什么鬼!怎么开不了!
What the fuck! It won't start!
万宝路到底跑哪儿去了?
- Where the fuck is Marlboro?
发动了! - 走!走!
- I got it!
- Go! Go!
不不不!
No, no, no!
等等 等等 等等!
Wait, wait, wait!
等等我!不要!
Wait! No!
跑快点 混蛋!跳上来!
Run, motherfucker! Jump in!
天啊!他们越来越近了 快开啊 伙计!
Holy shit! They're getting
closer Come on, man Go!
加速 加速!
- Go, go!
快啊!
Come on!
你是在逗我吗?
Are you kidding me?
我们居然在费卢杰停车加油?
We stopped for gas in Fallujah?
你个坑货!
You cheap fuck!
快开!
Go!
去你的万宝路!
- Fuck you, Marlboro!
该死
Fuck
该死 该死
Fuck Fuck
我们死定了!
We're gonna die!
你不是想开车去巴格达吗 你个混蛋!
You wanted to drive
to Baghdad, you asshole!
他们停车了
They're stopping
发生什么了?快看
What the fuck? Look
我去
Holy fuck, bro
操!太好了!
Oh, fuck! All right!
上帝保佑迪克・切尼时期的美国
God bless Dick Cheney's America!
这地方可真混乱 天啊
Look at this fucking place
Oh, my God
打扰了 长官?
Excuse me, sir?
什么事?
What?
外面有几个人想见你
There are some guys here to see you
几个人?
Some guys?
什么样的人?
What kind of guys?
嘿 万宝路!
Hey, Marlboro!
笑一个帅哥
Give us a smile, gorgeous
让我们看看你那一口大黄牙
Let me see those pearly yellows
你就像伊拉克版的汤姆・塞利克
You're like an Iraqi Tom Selleck, bro
你们是AEY的人?
You guys are AEY?
是的长官 我是戴维・佩豪斯
Yes, sir David Packouz
这是我同事埃佛隆・迪乌利
This is my colleague, Efraim Diveroli
我们通过话的
We spoke on the phone
我记得
I remember
这些都是你们开车送来的?
You drove these?
穿越死亡三角地带?
Through the Triangle of Death?
完全正确
Fucking A right we did
基普带哥几个去仓库 把钱付给他们
Kip, take these boys over to the cage,
get them paid
马上就去长官
Right away, sir
我之前看错你们了
I was wrong about you two
干得漂亮 小伙子们
Great fucking job, boys
非常漂亮
Great fucking job
我去死亡三角地带?
Holy shit, the Triangle of Death, bro?
没错 这就是AEY的信誉
That's right
That's the AEY guarantee, bitch
什么三角地带我们都能穿越 包括你妈妈的胯下
We drive through all triangles,
including your mom's
嘿 基普帮我们拍一张
Hey, Kip, snap a photo of us, pal
没问题
All right
准备好了吗?
Ready?
我头型如何? - 很好 漂亮的大背头
- How's my hair?
- It's good, slicked back
谢谢
- Thank you
拍好了 - 让我看看
- Got you
- Let me see it
你他妈就是赫尔穆特・牛顿
Helmut fucking Newton over here
得了吧 伙计
All right, man
完美 - 那就好
- Perfect
- All right, all right
我们去领工资吧
Let's go get fucking paid
天啊
Holy shit
很科幻 对吧?这里有整整122亿美元
Crazy, right? $122 billion
全是从教父那儿扣下来的
It's all seized
from the godfather himself
你们都称呼萨达姆・侯赛因 为教父?
You guys call
Saddam Hussein the godfather?
看看这一堆堆的钞票 不然你要怎么叫他?
Look at all this cash, bro
What would you call him?
280万
$28 million
在这里签字就行了 - 没问题
- Just sign here
- You got it
我们由军队护送到机场
We got a military escort
to the airport
然后离开了巴格达
and got the fuck out of Baghdad
在我们的军用背包里
There was almost $3 million in cash
有将近300万的现金
stuffed into our Army-issued duffel bags
你或许会认为在伊拉克死里逃生的经历
You might think
after barely surviving Iraq
会让我们点到为止
that we'd be done
但你想错了
But you'd be wrong
贝雷塔这单生意让我们名声大噪
You see, the Beretta deal
put us on the map
在那之后 我们的生意越做越多
After that, we started killing it
我们买了同款的保时捷
We bought matching Porsches
还在同一栋楼里买了两间公寓
We bought two apartments
in the same building
我的天啊
Oh, my God
我去伙计
- Holy shit, bro
噢!
Oh!
喔!
Whoo!
拉夫尔对于自己的提成非常满意
Ralph was so happy with his returns
所以他决定将原先的投资
that he increased his original investment
上涨到1千万
in AEY by $10 million
这样我们就拥有足够的资本谈下更多笔单子
That gave us enough capital
to pursue more deals
并且扩建我们的公司了
and expand the company
我们也正是这么做的
Which is exactly what we did
*这根本不是面包屑 这就是一整块派*
这一点强调多少次都不够
I cannot stress this enough
你们必须仔细翻阅这个网站
You need to be scouring this website
从早到晚
Day and night
每分钟都有更新
It is updated by the minute
网站上有数以万计的委托书
There are tens of thousands of
solicitations on this website
每一个委托书有40到50页
Each one is 40 to 50 pages long
如果你发现有意思的东西
If you see something interesting,
马上告知我
you bring it to me
如果你们及时通知了我
If you bring it to me,
我就能让你钱包鼓起来
I'll make you rich
事实上18个月前
Fact, 18 months ago,
那边的戴维还在帮别人打手枪赚钱
David here was jerking off guys for money
这不是事实
- Actually, that is not a fact
这就是事实
That is absolutely a fact
但现在他开的是保时捷
Now he drives a Porsche
这一切都归功于AEY
And that's all because of AEY
你们有什么问题吗?
Do you have any questions?
我有问题
Um, I have a question
AEY是什么意思?
What does AEY stand for?
你什么意思?是说它代表什么?
What do you mean? Like morally?
不 我是问它是什么单词的缩写?
No, I mean what do the letters mean?
这真是
That's fucking
那IBM是什么的缩写?什么都不是
What does IBM stand for? Nothing
只是这么叫听起来专业一点
It just It just sounds professional
事实上IBM指的是国际商用机器公司
Uh, actually, IBM stands for
International Business Machines
你说什么?
What did you say?
IBM指的是国际商用机器公司
IBM stands for
International Business Machines
快滚出去
Get the fuck out of here
我是认真的 这里不欢迎你
I'm serious
You're not going to work here
快滚出我的办公室 你个该死的书呆子!
Get the fuck out of my office,
you fucking nerd!
滚!
Go!
再说一遍 AEY不是什么的缩写
And for the record,
AEY doesn't stand for anything
操!真他妈混蛋
- Fuck! What a dick
还有人有问题吗?
Does anybody else have any questions?
你睡吧 我去看看
Sleep I got her
好了 好了
All right All right
嗨
Hi
我知道
I know
我知道 没事了
I know It's okay
好了
Okay
这是什么?
What?
36万支狙击步枪
360,000 SVD sniper rifles
1084万个GP-30手榴弹
1,084,000 GP-30 grenades
45万枚索克托导弹
45,000 SKO aviation rockets
五角大楼打算在接下来的30年里都对准阿富汗进攻
The Pentagon's arming the Afghans
for the next 30 years
所以正在集结一整支部队
They're building a whole army
等一下 那应该是打错了吧
Wait, that's got to be a typo
并没有
It's not
1亿发AK-47的子弹?
100 million rounds of AK-47 ammo?
兄弟 这可不是什么面包屑
Bro, these aren't crumbs
这可是块大大的完整的派
This is the whole fucking pie
对于国防承包商来讲
Among defense contractors,
这笔单子将会以"阿富汗问题"的名字出现
this would come to be known
as the Afghan deal
这将是AEY所面临的
It would be the biggest opportunity
最难能可贵的机会
AEY would ever see
我们必须拿下它
We had to go for it
所以如果想武装整个国家 你可以去哪儿?
So, where do you go
to arm an entire country?
*拉斯维加斯 内华达州*
维加斯是所有军方或者武器制造商
Vegas X is where
military and manufacturers
齐聚一起探讨最近战争问题的聚集地
come together to unveil
the latest in warfare
就好比主角是手榴弹的动漫大会
It's like Comic-Con with grenades
*2006年拉斯维加斯 国防科技博览会*
当然这里的大部分人都不知道AEY是什么
Sure, most of these guys
didn't know who AEY was
但我们把这一条视作是我们的优势
But we saw that as an advantage
清单带了吗? - 带了
- You got your list?
- Got it
感觉如何? - 还不错
- You feel good?
- Yeah, I feel pretty good
这跟在电话上谈生意完全是两码事
You know, this is different
than doing business on the phone
当他们看到我们的时候 第一反应肯定是这明明就是两个小屁孩
When they look at us,
they're going to see two kids
所以我们一定要摆出自己的姿态
So we have to show them our balls
明白
Got it
我们得扮演狠角色 明白吗?
We need to be fucking thugs,
you understand?
明白
Understood
好吧 我们上吧 一定要拿下
All right, good Let's kill this shit
但事实证明 这简直就是一场灾难
But it was a complete disaster
很快我们就明白了一点
We quickly learned that
即使我们能碰巧拿下"阿富汗问题"
even if we could land the Afghan deal,
但在运筹上仍然是个大问题
it would be a logistical nightmare
杰里 很高兴见到你
Jerry, good to see you
要想处理这种量级的单子
To source a deal of this magnitude
那就意味着
would mean piecing together
要和来自世界各地的不同供货商打交道
multiple vendors
from all around the world
喔喔
- Whoa, whoa
不是吧
Get out of here
也需要动用到数十次运输交通工具
It would require
dozens of shipping outfits
还有上百张许可证
and hundreds of permits
我们需要1亿发子弹
We need 100 million rounds
这些对于国防承包商大头来讲都不成问题
All that could be okay
for a major defense contractor
但对于我们来讲
But not for us
老实说我们还不够格
Honestly, we were out of our league
换1万的筹码
Change $10,000
今天运气如何?
Any luck today?
埃佛隆!
Efraim!
怎么了兄弟?
What's up, bro?
你去哪儿了?你为什么不接电话?
Where you been? Why aren't you
answering your phone?
我叫了妓女 有什么事吗?
I'm with a prostitute What's up?
你必须现在马上换衣服和我下楼
Okay, you need to get dressed
and come with me right now
好吧 给我
All right, uh, give me
38分钟
38 minutes
埃佛隆亨利・吉拉尔就在楼下的酒吧等我们
Efraim, Henry Girard is down at the bar,
waiting for us
别闹了
Get the fuck out of here
我是说真的
I'm dead serious
该死
Shit
好吧
Okay
亨利・吉拉尔在军火商里绝对算得上是传奇人物
Henry Girard was a legend
among arms dealers
当萨达姆・侯赛因以反人道罪被判处绞刑时
When they hung Saddam Hussein
for crimes against humanity
有传言称吊死他的那根绳子就是亨利卖的
it was said that Henry sold them the rope
嘿 亨利 抱歉我迟到了
Hey, Henry, sorry I'm late
这位就是我跟你提到的我的合伙人
This is my partner
I was telling you about
埃佛隆・迪乌利 - 很高兴认识你
- Efraim Diveroli
- Nice to meet you
见到你是我的荣幸
It's an absolute pleasure
亨利10分钟后就要去用餐了
Henry has a dinner in 10 minutes,
但我还是想要他亲自跟你讲
but I wanted you to hear this firsthand
我把清单给他看了 他能帮我们
I showed him the list and he can help
很好 具体是哪一部分的?
Great With which part?
全部
All of it
清单上有的 他都能想办法弄到
He can fill the whole order
所有东西? - 是的
- The whole order?
- Mmm-hmm
AK子弹也行?
Even the AK ammo?
没问题
Not a problem
你知道上面写的是1亿发对吧?
You do know it's
100 million rounds, right?
亨利在阿尔巴尼亚有认识的人
Henry has contacts in Albania
阿尔巴尼亚?
Albania?
他们花了几十年时间
They spent decades preparing
for a Western invasion that never came
那个国家就是一个巨大的兵工厂
That country is one giant arsenal
所有的武器应有尽有
It's all just sitting there
告诉他最激动人心的部分
Tell him the best part
他们正打算加入北大西洋公约组织
They're in the process of joining NATO,
所以他们必须把苏联时期的武器全部处理掉
so they have to dispose of all
of their Soviet era weapons
也就是把枪支全部拆卸掉分成小部件进行清理
They are literally dismantling it
and turning it into scrap
我可以花很少的钱把这些零件买回来
I can get most of the shit
for pennies on the dollar
还有另一个激动人心的部分
Now, tell him the other best part
现在坐在你面前的 就是这笔买卖属于我们独家代理
You're looking at the exclusive agent
for the whole fucking thing
这简直就跟变魔术一样
This was the magic bullet
一个供货商居然就可以搞定整个"阿富汗问题"
One supplier who could
fill the entire Afghan deal
这不仅给了我们竞争的机会
This wouldn't just put us in contention
我们甚至很有可能赢得代理权
We might actually win this thing
抱歉 我有一个问题
Sorry, I have a question
请讲
Sure
你既然有这么多关系
With that kind of hookup
为什么不自己出价自己干呢?
why don't you just bid
on the contract yourself?
要听真话吗?
Full disclosure?
我被禁止和美国政府进行任何的商业往来
I'm barred from doing any business
with the US government
我在监控名单上
I'm on a watch list
恐怖分子监控名单?
Like a terrorist watch list?
是的
Mmm-hmm
明白了 - 等等你说什么?
- Got it
- Wait, what?
那AK子弹要多少钱?
Okay, how much for the AK ammo?
1发10美分 - 太他妈便宜了
- 10 cents a round
- That's fucking amazing
那运输方面呢?
And what about shipping?
由俄罗斯飞行员驾驶的苏联伊留申76式飞机
You can get Ilyushin 76
through Russian pilots
每趟8万
80K per flight
抱歉 你是说恐怖分子监控名单上有你的名字?
I'm sorry, you're on
a terrorist watch list?
搞什么!
What the fuck!
你是国防部的吗?反应别这么大 伙计
Do you work for Homeland Security?
Relax, bro
你们最好再好好商量一下
You two should probably talk this over
我们会的 而且我们非常感兴趣
We will But we are very interested
很好 我的飞机明早10点起飞
Good My flight leaves
tomorrow morning at 10:00
我不能在这里待超过48小时的时间
I can't spend more than 48 hours
in this dump
我总是这么说 最多只能在维加斯浪两天
That's what I always say
Vegas is a two-day town
我说的是美国
I was talking about America
这可是苏联集团的非标准武器
We're talking exclusive access
to a stockpile
和子弹库存的专属访问权
of Soviet Bloc non-standard
weapons and ammo
这肯定能帮我们拿下这笔生意的
That's going to win this deal for us
他在恐怖分子的监控名单上!
He's on a terrorist watch list!
管这么多干嘛 如果有人带剪刀上飞机 都可能上那名单
Whatever People end up on that list
for bringing scissors onto an airplane!
他绝不是因为这个上的名单
That's not why he's on the list
听着 国防部想要在全世界资源如此短缺的情况下
Look, the Pentagon wants
100 million rounds of AK-47 ammo
要1亿发的AK-47子弹
in the middle of a worldwide shortage
你觉得这么多子弹从何而来?
Where do you think
they think that's going to come from?
就是从跟他一样的不法分子那儿来
A bunch of shady motherfuckers
like that guy
这就是工作
This is the job
你必须和那些美国政府不能直接与之
To do business with the people in places
产生商业来往的人做生意
the US government
can't do business with directly
就这么简单
It's as simple as that
操!
Fuck!
嘿 小伙子们
Hey, boys
我们讨论过了 我们愿意和你合作
So we discussed it,
and we'd like to move forward
太好了 恭喜
Fantastic Congratulations
但我们必须验验货 - 没问题
- But we have to see the merchandise
- Oh, of course
亲自去验
On site, in person
你们去过阿尔巴尼亚吗?
You guys ever been to Albania?
老实说 不是你昨晚提到的话
Honestly, until last night
我还真不知道这个国家真的存在
I didn't even know it was
a real fucking country
噢 那个地方挺美的
Oh, it's a beautiful place
先进屋吧 我给我的手下打个电话 叫他们安排一下
Come on in I'll call my guy
and we'll set it up
阿尔巴尼亚有很多特质
Albania is a lot of things
但美丽的地方绝对不是其中之一
But a beautiful place is not one of them
我们换乘了两趟飞机
It took us three separate flights
飞了整整22个小时才到这里
and 22 hours just to get there
亨利的手下派了一个司机
Henry's people sent a driver
去机场接我们
to pick us up at the airport
而这个家伙一直讲个不停
and the guy would not stop talking
我倒下了 但她又让我活过来
I fall over, she revive me
但所有的这一切都没有浇灭埃佛隆的热情
But none of that diminished
Efraim's enthusiasm
他始终坚信这一次我们一定能大有作为
He really believed
this could be the answer
欢迎你们 AEY
Welcome, AEY
我是于利・皮纳瑞
I am Yili Panari,
阿尔巴利亚最大的武器出口公司的老板
head of Albania's largest
military export company
我是埃佛隆・迪乌利 很高兴认识你
Efraim Diveroli Good to see you
这位是我的合作伙伴戴维・佩豪斯
This is my business associate,
David Packouz
很高兴认识你 - 你好吗?
- Glad to meet you
- How you doing?
额
Uh
谢谢你们准备的标语
Thank you for the sign
专程为你们准备的
Oh It's for you
我知道 所以我才谢谢你们嘛
Yes, I know
I said thank you for the sign
给我们看看货吧
So, show us what you got
这是什么地方?
What is this place?
阿尔巴利亚军队的储物室
Storage for the Albanian army
这个国家还有700多间这样的地方
We have 700 more like it
across the country
你们有700间像这样的仓库?
You have 700 warehouses like this?
不仅仅是仓库
Not just warehouse
我们还利用教堂医院学校存放装备
We use church, hospital, school
阿尔巴利亚是全世界武器最多的国家
Albania is most armed country
in the world
嘿 真棒恭喜你们
Hey, that's cool Congrats, bro
这里就像个博物馆一样
It was like
a fucking museum in there
这里的很多武器 自冷战之后
Most of this shit hadn't seen daylight
就再也没见过光
since the Cold War
但这对我们来讲不是什么问题
But that didn't matter to us
我们唯一在意的就是AK子弹
All we cared about was the AK ammo
别担心 你们需要的东西我们这里多的是
It's okay We have plenty
of what you came for
所有的集装箱里都装满了你们想要的子弹
All these containers
are filled with your bullets
你什么意思 所有的子弹都在这里?
What do you mean,
all the bullets are right here?
一共有1亿2千6百万发
126 million rounds
我去
Fuck me
准备好大开眼界吧
Yeah Fuck us all
这些子弹放了多久了?
How old are these?
30年也有可能40年了 这些AK-47子弹
30, maybe 40 years AK-47 bullets
如果保存妥当一辈子都不会坏
can last forever if properly stored
好吧 那这些保存得怎么样?
Right Well, how were these stored?
谁他妈在乎这些保存得好不好?
Uh, who gives a fuck
how these were stored?
重要的是还能不能用
All that matters is they fucking work
它们还能用吗?
Do they work?
你自己试试
You try
子弹都能用
They fucking worked
整个国防市场都在争抢这笔买卖
The entire defense industry
was scrambling over this deal
而帮助我们赢得投标的关键就装在这23个
And the key to it was sitting
in 23 shipping containers
位于世界另一端的 破旧不堪的仓库集装箱里
in the back of a rusted out warehouse
on the other side of the world
*迈阿密 佛罗里达州*
我们回去的时间恰巧赶上
We got back with just enough time
提交投标的最后期限
to submit our bid
before the government's deadline
接下来就是无尽的等待
And then we waited
我们等了5个月
We waited five months
爸爸
Pa
戴维!
David!
那是埃佛隆? - 什么?
- Is that Efraim?
- What?
是吗?  - 戴维!
- Is it?
- David!
我们赢了!
We fucking won!
天啊 我们拿下了"阿富汗问题"
Holy shit We won the Afghan deal
什么? - 我们拿下了"阿富汗问题"!
- What?
- We won the Afghan deal!
我们赢了吗? - 赢了!
- We won?
- We fucking won!
兄弟!你不是在寻我开心吧?
Bro! Are you fucking kidding me?
我们真的赢了! - 是的 他妈的!
- We fucking won!
- Yeah, motherfucker!
太棒了!天啊!
Yeah! Yeah, motherfucker!
在我们开工之前
Before we could begin,
AEY还是必须经过政府的审查
AEY still needed to be vetted
by the government
整个过程让人郁闷纠结
It's a pain-in-the ass process
其中包括3个独立的审计
involving three separate audits
以及一场面试
and an in-person interview
审计是最头疼的部分
The audits were the biggest hurdle
我们连一个真正的会计员都没有
I mean, we didn't even
have a real bookkeeper
我们甚至连一本书都没有
We didn't have real books
我们必须伪造AEY在过去3年里的
We had to fabricate AEY's accounting
财务情况
going back three years
分类账银行结单 还有假冒的订购单
Ledgers, bank statements,
phony purchase orders,
所有的一切都是伪造的
we forged it all
两周之后 我们来到了伊利诺斯州的
Two weeks later, we were in Rock Island,
罗克艾兰和来自美国军队的
Illinois for our big meeting
采购专员进行最为重要的面试
with procurement officers
from the US Military
我们紧张到快窒息
We were pretty fucking nervous
所以埃夫拉伊建议 我们在停车场先爽一发
So Efraim thought it'd be a good idea
to get high in the parking lot
*岩岛市军械库(华盛顿州)*
等等
Hold up
我们走路的声音听起来是不是不止两个人?
Does it sound like
we're more than two people right now?
没错
Yeah
这后劲可真大
It was really strong shit
好吧
Okay
非常好
This is very impressive
Very impressive
说实话 看了你们的历史记录 我们一开始还很担心
Frankly, we were a tad concerned
with your performance history
你们是否能处理好这种量级的单子
against a deal of this size
但在见到你们本人后
But after meeting you two face to face,
我们感觉自己选对人了
we feel like we're in good hands
on this one
我们不会让你们失望的
Well, we won't let you down,
先生们
sirs
更别提
Not to mention,
你们出的价也节省了我们不少纠结的时间
your bid was far too attractive
for us to pass up
谢谢 很高兴听到你们这么讲
Thank you I mean, that's great to hear
because we really worked hard on this
抱歉 打断一下
Sorry Excuse me
你们之中刚刚有人讲
One of you just said
我们的出价非常具有吸引力
our bid was too attractive to pass up
此话怎讲 能说得具体点吗?
What did you mean by that, exactly?
他的意思就是说 你们的出价比所有人都要低
He means you boys lowballed
the shit out of your competition
我知道
Yeah Uh
但是低多少呢?
By how much?
几百万
Millions
好吧
Okay
我很好奇
Just for me I
具体是几百万?
I'm curious, how many millions?
严格上来讲 我们不能跟你们讨论这个问题的
Well, technically, we're not supposed to
discuss that with you,
但管他这么多呢
but what the hell
你们出的价比出价第二低的人还要再低5300万
You guys came in $53 million
lower than the nearest competition
操!操!
Fuck! Fuck!
他妈的!
Motherfucker!
5千3百万
$53 million
我们很好
We're okay
往好的方面想想
Look at the bright side
这是历史上第一次
For once, the American taxpayer
美国的纳税人在国防问题上花值了钱
is getting a good deal
on a defense contract
谁他妈在乎纳税人啊
Man, fuck the American taxpayer
*我们遇到大麻烦了*
有人吗?
Hello?
伊兹?
Iz?
嘿 艾拉 嗨
Hey, Ella Hi
你还好吗 亲爱的?
How are you, sweetie?
嘿 你知道她那双蓝色的凉鞋放哪儿了吗?
Hey Do you know
where her blue sandals are?
噢 嘿
Oh, hey
额 我也不清楚
Um, I'm not sure
等一下 我们能谈谈吗?
But listen, can we talk for a sec?
没问题
Mmm-hmm
我要回阿尔巴利亚几个星期
I need to go back to Albania
for a couple weeks
最多1个月
A month, tops
好的 没问题
Sure No problem
嘿 出什么事了吗?
Hey, what's going on?
我要带艾拉回去跟我妈住一段时间
Ella and I are going to stay
with my mom for a while
什么?你在说什么?
What? What are you talking about?
伊兹出什么事了?
Iz, what happened?
你为什么不告诉我 你去过伊拉克?
How come you didn't tell me
you went to Iraq?
我在你的电脑上查找水管工的电话
I was looking for the plumber's number
然后看到了那张照片
on your computer and I saw the photos
你听我解释
I can explain
你说过你从来没离开过约旦的酒店
You said you never left
the hotel room in Jordan
我知道因为我不想让你担心
I know Because I didn't
want to freak you out
为什么每次我抓到你撒谎
Why is it every time I catch you in a lie
你总想说服我 你这么做是出于对我的考虑?
you try to convince me
that you lied for my benefit?
你为什么就不肯承认自己是个骗子?
At what point do you
just admit you're a liar?
伊兹 求你别这么说
Iz, would you stop, please?
我们说过要互相坦诚
We said we'd tell each other everything
你发过誓的! - 我知道!是我搞砸了
- You promised!
- I know! Okay, I fucked up
你还有什么秘密瞒着我?
What else aren't you telling me?
没了 - 我不信
- Nothing
- No
真的
Seriously
我现在什么秘密都没有
You know everything now
好吧 你怎么不问我为什么要找水管工的电话?
Okay Aren't you going to ask me
why I called the plumber?
对 为什么啊?
Yeah, sure What happened?
客房厕所的水管有点漏水
The pipe is leaking in the guest bathroom
我去检查结果发现了这个
I found this
我猜猜你是不想让我担心?
Let me guess
You didn't want to freak me out?
等一下
Okay, hold on
我是在水池底下藏了钱
So I hid some money under the sink
这有什么大不了的?
What's the big deal?
大不了的是这些钱 你是背着我藏的!
The big deal is you hid it from me!
不 我没有!
No, I didn't!
那你是怕谁拿走?
Then who did you hide it from?
我也不知道这么做太蠢了 你是对的
I don't know It was stupid You're right
等你有更好的理由的时候 再来找我们
We're going to leave
before you think of something else to say
伊兹 对不起
Iz, I'm sorry
伊兹!
- Iz!
该死
Oh, fuck
嘿 你好吗 伙计?
Hey, what's up, man?
你好吗?
What's up?
刚准备好离开
Just getting ready to leave
这是什么?
What is that?
我想谢谢你愿意去那边出差
I just wanted to thank you
for agreeing to go on this trip
这些年你为公司
It's not lost on me,
做出的牺牲 我都记在心上
the sacrifice you're making
for this company
对此我非常感谢
And I really appreciate it
"送给我的搭档 戴维 世界在你脚下"
"To my partner, David
The world is yours"
《疤面煞星》里的台词 - 我记得
- It's from Scarface
- Of course, man I remember
谢谢
Thank you
不用
Yeah
嘿 在我走之前
Uh, hey, before I go,
我想
I just wanted
这是什么?
What's this?
是我们的合作合约 7：3分成
It's our partnership agreement 70-30
我想弄得正式点
I just wanted to make it official
当然没问题
Yeah, of course
这是个好主意 - 那好
- It's a good idea
- Cool
天啊 要在阿尔巴利亚待8个星期啊
Man, eight fucking weeks in Albania
伊兹要一辈子都不理我了
Iz is going to hate me forever
不 她以后一定会每天都把你服侍得妥妥帖帖的
No, she's going to suck your cock
every day for a year
因为我们很快就会有3千万进账了
Because we're on the verge
of making $30 million
没错
Yeah, man
加油 把它拿下
Go crush it
谢谢你 伙计
Thanks, bro
好了
Nice
嘿 我是伊兹 有事请留言
Hey, you've reached Iz
You know what to do
别这样伊兹 别不接我电话啊
- Come on, Iz Don't cut me off like this
我现在在阿尔巴尼亚在酒店里
I'm in Albania, at the hotel
这边的号码 我已经告诉你妈妈了
Left the number with your mom
求你快回我电话吧
And if you could please just call me back
我真的很想你好吗?
because I really miss you Okay?
我爱你
And I love you
再见
Bye
早上好 伙计
Good morning, buddy
嘿 巴什基姆
Hey, Bashkim
我给你买了早点 在这边麦当劳买的
Oh, I bring you Kolonat
It's our McDonald's
我不饿 不过还是谢谢
Yeah, I'm good But thanks
现在出发吗?
We go to work now?
不对 不不不 我说过我要两辆卡车
Uh-huh No, no, no
I said I need two trucks
现在这里只来了一辆
Yeah, you just got the one here right now
听着 现在我的货运飞机就在机场等着的
Yeah Look, I got a cargo
plane sitting at the airport
是的 我知道我知道
Yeah, I know I know
嘿 我等会再打给你
Hey, let me call you right back
嘿 停一下!停车!停车!
Hey, stop! Stop, stop!
等等 等等 等等!嘿快停车!
Hold up, hold up, hold up!
Hey, turn that off!
这他妈是什么?
What the fuck is that?
你从哪儿弄来的?
Where did you get this?
哟!什么事?
Yo! What's up?
嘿 伙计我们有麻烦了
Hey, man, we got a problem
你现在在哪儿? - 我在酒吧
- Where you at?
- I'm at Liv, bro
准备钓几个古巴的漂亮美眉
Trying to bang some Cuban chick
who's waiting for me at my table
怎么了 出什么事了?
Why, what do we got?
我就直说了
Let me get this straight
I'm in Albania right now
我现在在阿尔巴尼亚 冻得屎都要出来了
freezing my ass off
而你却在酒吧逍遥快活?
You're at Liv, trying to get laid?
戴维 这边现在是凌晨1点
David, it's 1:00 am here
我刚刚吸了点大麻
I'm blowing off some steam
凌晨1点 刚好就是你应该待在办公室的时间
Yeah, 1:00 am is when you're
supposed to be at the office
因为我们就是这个时候
because that's the middle of fucking day
跟其他国家的人做生意的
in every country we do business with
听我说 AK子弹的货出了问题
Look, we got a problem
with the AK ammunition
什么问题? - 它们是中国产的
- What kind of problem?
- It's Chinese
中国?那是什么意思?
Chinese, bro?
What does that even mean, Chinese?
我是说这批子弹都是来自中国的
It means it's from China
你在说什么?验货的时候我也在场啊 我检查过那批子弹了
What are you talking about?
I was there, I saw the ammo
我也确认过啊
We both did
我不知道该怎么跟你说
Yeah, look, I don't know what to tell you
我们被耍了好吗?我们被骗了
They fucked us Okay? We got played
等一下 你怎么那些子弹是中国产的?
Hold on How do you even
know it's Chinese?
因为每一个箱子外面都写着中文
There's Chinese writing
on every fucking crate
相信我绝对是中国产的
Trust me, it's Chinese
好吧
Yeah
亨利你搞什么!
Henry, what the fuck!
这两天我们一直在给你打电话!
We've been trying to reach you
for two days!
这里是埃佛隆和戴维
It's Efraim and David
我们碰到大麻烦了
We have a serious fucking problem
我在听
I'm listening
那些AK子弹全是中国产的
The AK ammunition, it's Chinese
怎么你觉得那群被塔利班打得屁滚尿流的
What, you think the Afghans
who are getting
阿富汗人会在意他们的子弹是哪里产的吗?
shot up by the Taliban give a shit
where their ammo comes from?
他们不在意 但五角大楼就不一样了
No, but the Pentagon does
亨利 你知道我们不能用中国产的东西!
Henry, you know we can't use Chinese!
美国对于中国有禁运令
America has an embargo against China
你只叫你的手下 给我们看了一箱阿尔巴尼亚的子弹
You had your boys show us the one crate
of Albanian ammo in the entire country
抱歉 有人阻止你们
I'm sorry, did anyone prevent you
from inspecting the other crates?
你们有没有想过要问清楚子弹的原产地在哪儿?
Did you even bother to ask
what the country of origin was?
谁他妈会问这些问题?
Who the fuck would ask that?
亨利 我面前是1亿发……
Henry, I'm staring at 100 million rounds
你卖给我们的非法中国造子弹
of illegal Chinese ammunition
that you sold us
我们应该怎么办?
What are we supposed to do?
该怎么办怎么办!
Do your fucking job!
美国政府会睁一只眼闭一只眼的
The US government
wants to look the other way
不要画蛇添足
Don't give them a reason not to
还有既然现在是你们在处理发货的问题就要分清楚
And while you're at it,
learn the difference between
"我们遇到麻烦了"和"你遇到麻烦了"的区别
"We have a problem"
and "You have a problem"
该死!
Fuck!
*这听起来好像不合法*
我们完蛋了 这些子弹就是一堆破铜烂铁
We were fucked
The ammo was worthless
而我被困在阿尔巴尼亚 尝试联系东欧的其他供货商
and I was stuck in Albania
trying to piece together new suppliers
希望能把货拼凑完整
from all over Eastern Europe
我的天啊
Holy shit
你来这干嘛伙计?
What the fuck are you doing here, man?
我有计划了
I have a big idea
你是怎么进来的?
How did you get in my room?
他们让我进来的
They let me in
我是个很有信誉的人
I'm a trustworthy guy
他们不仅放我进来 还给我准备了客房服务
Not only did they let me in,
they brought me room service
总之 我有很好的主意
Anyway, I have a big fucking idea
是吗?是什么?
Yeah? What's that?
我们重新包装怎么样?
What if we repack?
包装什么?
Repack what?
子弹啊!
The bullets!
把它们全部都重新包装?
What if we repack them all?
1亿发?
100 million rounds?
戴维 这不是不可能的
David, it can be done
你这样想啊 这样做还能减少我们运货的花销
Think about it
We'll also save a fortune on shipping
我们把那些又大又重的木盒子
We trade out all the big,
heavy wooden crates
换成轻便的纸箱
for light cardboard boxes
但那还是中国造的子弹啊
Yeah, but it would still be Chinese ammo
拿着条毛巾来说吧
Look at this towel Okay?
上面写的是土耳其制造
Turkish Made in Turkey
不再是了 它现在就是一条阿尔巴尼亚毛巾了
Not anymore Now it's an Albanian towel
只有当外包装上写明它是中国造时它才是中国造
It's only Chinese
if the packaging says it's Chinese
我知道 但这样做是不合法的呀
Yeah But I mean, that's
also fucking illegal, man
我们只有两个选择
We have two options
要么重新包装然后寄出去
We either repack this shit and send it off
要么和这3亿的大单子说拜拜
or we can walk away
from a $300 million-deal
你想怎么办?
What do you want to do?
当你这么比较的时候 其实就只有一个选择了
When you put it like that
there's really only one option
我们的司机巴什基姆给我们介绍了一个他的朋友
Our driver Bashkim
introduced us to his friend
他在地拉那外拥有一家包装储物公司
who owned a boxing and storage company
out of Tirana
他叫恩维尔 是我的发小
This is Enver I grew up with him
很高兴认识你恩维尔
Nice to meet you, Enver
我也是 巴什基姆把你们遇到的问题稍微跟我提了一下
You too Bashkim told me
a little about your situation
简单来说 我们现在的包装太重了
Yeah, look, to put it simply,
we have a weight problem
我们要运输数量巨大的子弹
We're shipping
a large quantity of ammunition
从阿尔巴尼亚到阿富汗
from Albania to Afghanistan
而现在它们是装在一个铁皮盒里
Right now, it's packed in heavy tins
外面还有一个非常重的木箱
inside big wooden crates
我们想要转而用塑料袋……
And what we would like to do
装这些子弹
is to transfer those bullets
into plastic bags
然后再把袋子放进
and then put those in double-walled,
双层的纤维板里
corrugated fiberboard boxes
你知道那是什么吗?
Do you know what those are?
我当然知道 为什么要换包装?
Yeah, of course For what reason?
刚刚不是说了吗
We just told you
这个地方的人怎么都这样啊?
What the fuck is it with this country?
原始的包装 它的份量太重了
The original packaging, it's too heavy
然后箱子有特别多 所以我们想提高效率
Too many crates We need to streamline
好的 有多少个箱子?
Okay How many crates?
很多子弹 都有1亿发昵
A lot It's 100 million
rounds of ammunition
我明白 但是具体有多少个箱子?
Understood But how many actual crates?
68520个
We have 68,520 crates
我有见过
I've seen it
非常壮观
It's fucking crazy
算好了
Done
50个人工作的话 需要8周时间完成
So 50 men, eight weeks
10万块我就愿意做
I can do it for $100,000
10万美元?
100,000 US dollars?
是的
Yeah
请等一下 - 我们讨论一下
- Give us a second
- Yeah One second, please
好的 我要非常严肃地跟你讨论一个问题
Okay I'm going to talk very seriously
想要把笑憋住非常不容易
It was hard not to laugh
不仅是因为这个人帮我们挽回了这次交易
I mean, not only was this guy
saving the entire deal,
并且重新包装所有子弹
but by repacking all the ammo
会提高我们的利润将近3百万
we would increase our profit margin
by almost $3 million
今晚晚餐在哪儿吃?
Where should we get dinner tonight?
酒店旁边有家馆子味道还不错
There's this place by the hotel
It's pretty good
那好就这么定了
Okay All right, go ahead
成交
Okay, deal
最后的效果比我们预想中还要好
It was even better than we thought
我们用轻便的纤维板代替笨重的木质结构
We were trading heavy wooden crates
for light cardboard boxes
一个塑料袋只重8盎司
Eight ounce tins for plastic bags
通过重新包装子弹
By repacking the ammo,
我们将总重量减轻了约180吨
we would lighten our overall load
by 180 tons
那可是180吨啊!
180 fucking tons!
那意味着更少的航运次数更轻的飞机以及更少的耗油量
That meant fewer flights
using lighter planes burning less fuel
所有的这一切节省下来的开支都将进入我们自己的荷包
Which all added up to more money for us
2007年12月8日这一天
On December 8th, 2007,
AEY将第一批5百万发子弹送往了
AEY delivered the first 5 million rounds
阿富汗军队
to the Afghan army
所有的一切都进行得很顺利
It went off without a hitch
快嘛 再说一遍 宝贝 快点
Come on, just say it once, sweetie
Come on
叫"爸爸"叫"爸爸"
Say "dada" Say "dada"
我们必须得下了 戴维
We really have to go, David
别啊 嘿 再聊5分钟嘛 求你了 求你了
No, hey, five more minutes,
please? Please?
我们要吃饭了 妈妈在催了
We're about to eat My mom's waiting
艾拉 给爸爸再见
Ella, wave goodbye to Daddy Hmm
再见 艾拉
Bye-bye, Ella
圣诞快乐 我爱你
Merry Christmas I love you
嘿 你能把她先抱给你妈照顾 我们单独说两句吗?
Hey, can you give her to your mom
so that we can talk for a minute?
抱歉 戴维
I'm sorry, David
我们过几天再打给你好吗?
We'll call you in a couple days Okay?
再见
Bye
嘿 我是戴维
Hey, this is David
伙计 你想听个很操蛋的事吗?
Bro, you want to hear
something totally fucked up?
圣诞快乐 埃佛隆
Merry Christmas, Efraim
今天是圣诞吗?
It's Christmas?
所以公司里才没人
That's why nobody's here
我还打算把所有人都开除了呢
I was about to fire the entire office
话说回来 我之前去那边的时候
Anyway, when I was over there,
和巴什基姆说了几句
I was talking to our boy, Bashkim
你知道他叔叔
Did you know his uncle
在阿尔巴尼亚国防部上班吗?
works at the Albanian defense ministry?
不 我不知道
No, I didn't know that
他是在那儿上班
Well, he does
所以我就问他 "你知道我觉得什么很有意思吗 巴什基姆?"
So I said, "You know what would be
interesting to me, Bashkim?
"我一直很好奇 亨利每发AK子弹付多少钱给阿尔巴尼亚人"
"I'd be curious to know what Henry
is paying the Albanians for the AK ammo"
埃佛隆?
Efraim?
你猜他发现了什么?
Do you know what he found out?
那个混蛋每发子弹只付给他们25美分
That motherfucker is paying
two and a half cents a round
但他竟然收我们4倍的价钱!
He's charging us a 400% markup!
那又怎样?我们也是这么干的啊
Yeah So what? We do the same thing
但这是我们谈的合同
Yeah, but this is our contract
而因为他和他该死的中国造子弹 差点害我们洗白
And we almost lost it because of him
and his Chinese fucking bullets
但我们现在不是做得好好的吗
But we didn't lose it
这不是重点!
That's not the point!
我要想个法子把这个混蛋从我们的生意中踢出去
I want to figure out a way
to cut this cocksucker out of the deal
埃佛隆 别这样
Efraim, stop
不 你听我说
No, listen to me
我是认真的
I'm serious, man
我们想赚钱
We're making money, okay?
他也想赚钱 互不干扰 一切都在井然有序地进行着
He's making money,
the whole thing is fucking working
别搞砸了
Don't mess with it
我才不管这么多 他在搞事情!
I don't give a fuck He's ripping us off!
我是很认真的
Look, I'm serious, okay?
如果你要是敢掺一脚 我马上乘最快航班回来
I'm going to be on the next flight
out of here if you pull that shit
喔 伙计 你不必威胁我
Whoa Bro, you don't have to threaten me
好吗?我是你搭档
All right? I'm your partner
没错 但你的表现让我很不放心
Yeah, it doesn't always feel like that
这笔生意是我找到的 我在这边
I found this deal And I'm over here
拼死工作 而你坐在迈阿密的办公室里整天就帮倒忙
doing all the work and you're in Miami
trying to sabotage it
我怎么又帮倒忙了?
How am I sabotaging it?
你想教训亨利 就像你教训其他人一样
By trying to fuck over Henry,
the way you fuck over everybody else
你说的没错 亨利也是我们的合伙人
You're right Henry's our partner
没有他 就没有这笔生意
He's the reason we got this deal
我只是想 为我们打抱不平 但是可能过头了
I was just looking out for us
and I took it too far
别担心 兄弟 我不会动他的
Don't sweat it, bro I'll leave it alone
谢谢你
Thank you
我们现在不能意气用事 伙计
We can't push our luck
with this shit, man
好的 我过几天再打给你再见
All right, I'll talk to you soon Bye
喔 干什么?嘿
Whoa What the fuck? Hey
该死!住手
Fuck! Stop
别打了!我不明白你们在说什么!
Stop! I don't understand!
现在明白了吗?
Do you understand now?
明白了
Yeah Yes
你们真的认为能把我从自己的买卖中踢出去吗?
Did you really think
you could cut me out of my own deal?
求你了
Please
操
Fuck
戴维 我们需要谈谈
David, we need to talk
现在不行
Now's not a good time
我现在还没收到钱
I have not been paid yet
你说什么?这个月的钱吗?
What do you mean? Like for the month?
从开始到现在
Ever
一分钱都没打给你?
You haven't been paid anything?
你的同伴连电话都不接
Your partner doesn't return phone calls
必须马上付钱给我的手下
My guys need to be paid
不然他们就要停工
They are going to stop work
戴维 我知道你们重新包装子弹的
David, I know the real reason
真正目的
that you want ammunition repacked
恩维尔 你听我说
Okay, look, Enver Listen to me
我现在要马上飞回迈阿密 过一个星期就回来
I gotta fly to Miami right now
I'll be back in a week
我向你保证
But I promise you,
我下飞机后做的第一件事
the first thing that
I'm going do when I land
就是确保把你们的钱打过来 好吗?
is make sure
you get your money wired, okay?
好的
Okay
戴维
David
去机场
Airport, let's go
戴维
David
我要赶去坐飞机 下个星期就回来
Look, I'm late for a flight
I'll be back next week
她说她丈夫昨晚没回家
She said her husband
didn't come home last night
好吧 你想让我帮你什么?
Okay, what do you want me to do?
她非常担心 因为他平常不会这样
She's very worried It is not like him
告诉她 我不认识她丈夫
Tell her I don't know her husband
你丈夫是谁?
Who's your husband?
巴什基姆
Bashkim
没人再收到任何关于巴什基姆的消息
No one ever heard
from Bashkim again
没有留言 也没找到尸体
They never found a note,
they never found a body
他就这么人间蒸发了
He just fell off the planet
我受够阿尔巴尼亚了
I was done with Albania
我再也不会回去了
I was never going back
嗨
Hi
嘿
Hey
我回阿尔巴尼亚的原因是重新包装那批子弹
The reason I went to Albania
was to repackage Chinese ammunition
将它们的真实产地进行伪装 然后再卖给美国政府
so we could disguise it
and sell it to the US government
这听起来好像不合法
That sounds illegal
是的 但一切都结束了
It is But I'm done
我发誓不管接下来发生什么
I swear, no matter what happens
for the rest of my life
我永远都不会再向你撒谎了
I'm never going to lie to you again
好吧
Mmm-hmm
我真的好爱你 伊兹
I love you so much, Iz
你的鼻子怎么了?
What happened to your nose?
我被阿尔巴尼亚的黑帮绑架了
I was kidnapped by Albanian gangsters
应该是骨折了 - 我的天啊
- I think it's broken
- Oh, my God
我打算重新做回按摩理疗师
I think I'm going to go back
to being a massage therapist
可以吗?
Is that okay?
可以
Yes
只要你回来就好
It was always okay
嘿 你回来了
Hey, you're back
喔!
Whoa!
兄弟 你回来干什么?你的脸怎么了?
Bro, what are you doing back?
What happened to your face?
这上面有截止到今天所有送往阿富汗的货物
That's everything that's been delivered
on the Afghan deal
我想要我那部分的钱 我不干了
I want my cut I'm out
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
他拿了一把枪抵着我的头
He put a fucking gun to my head, man
谁 亨利吗?
Who, Henry?
你说过不会乱来的
You said that you were going
to leave it alone
噢 该死
Oh, fuck
是我的错
I fucked up
我不干了 埃佛隆
I'm done, Efraim
听着 你其实不用回来的
Look, you don't have to go back
我雇了一个新人伊万
I hired this new guy, Ivan
他会说阿尔巴尼亚语 - 我不干了
- He speaks Albanian
- I'm done
怎么你觉得我身边有4百万闲钱可以随时给你?
What, do you think
I just got 4 million bucks laying around?
我已经想过了
I've thought it through
我要分4成
I'll take 40 cents on the dollar
我也想过了
Yeah, I thought it through too
这样如何?
How about this?
你一成都别想分?
How about zero cents on the dollar?
我提醒你 我们可是有合约的
Let me remind you that we have a contract
去你妈的合约!
Fuck your contract!
如果我请你帮我建一栋房子
If I asked you to build me a house,
这房子才刚完成一半 你却告诉我你要退出
and you quit after building me
half a house,
你觉得我要付你那一半的钱吗?
you think I owe you half the money?
你觉得这很好玩吗 戴维?
Is this a fucking joke, David?
给你两个星期的时间 否则到时候给你打电话的就是我的律师了
You have two weeks
Otherwise, you'll hear from my lawyer
谁 沃伦吗?
- Who, Warren?
你说的是沃伦吗?他也是我的律师
Are you talking about Warren?
He's my lawyer too
还是我把他介绍给你的
I introduced you to him
该死的沃伦
Fucking Warren
操!
Fuck!
这里是AEY 请问你找谁?
AEY
How may I direct your call?
*如果我真想要你的命 你早就死了*
*三个月后*
我们战斗
We fight
为了家人
Fight with our families,
为了我们的合作伙伴
fight with our business associates
有时也为了我们的朋友
Sometimes we fight with our friends
如果上帝在场
If God were here,
我们也会为他而战
we'd probably fight with Him too
埃佛隆对于发生的事情非常抱歉
Efraim has a heavy heart
over what's happened
恕我直言 拉夫尔 但我感觉 你可能还没认清他的真面目
No offense, Ralph, but I'm not sure
you've ever met the real Efraim
他是很复杂的年轻人
He's a complicated young man
但他只是想和你坐下来好好谈谈
But he just wants to sit down and talk
他想和你和解
Find a fair solution
所以他叫我来帮忙调解
He's asked me to mediate
让我帮帮你们吧 戴维
Let me help you, David
我不知道我准备好没有
I just don't know
if I'm ready yet
他来了
All right, here he is
嘿 兄弟
Hey, bro
很高兴见到你
Good to see you
抱歉发生了这么多事情
Sorry things have gotten so crazy
我也是
Yeah Me too
需要点什么餐吗?
You having anything, hon?
给我一杯咖啡就好 谢谢
I'll just have a coffee Thanks
我想了很久
I've thought about it a lot
还是觉得不能让你就这么两手空空地离开
And I don't want you to walk away
from this empty-handed
好啊
Cool
所以我让沃伦起草了一份离职合同
So I had Warren draft up
a severance agreement
我觉得挺公平的
And I think it's pretty fair
我准备在接下来的4年里每年付给你5万块
I'm prepared to pay you 50K per year
for the next four years
也就是20万?
200 grand?
你是在开玩笑吗?
Is this a fucking joke, man?
这就是你所谓的调解?
Is this what you meant by mediation?
因为你们既没有签订合同
In all fairness, there was never
也没有签订合伙协议 所以这已经算不错的了
a partnership agreement,
no prior contract
我有比合伙协议更好的东西
Yeah I have something better
than a partnership agreement
我有证据
I have proof
在我离开阿尔巴尼亚之前 我把所有东西都拿走了
Before I left Albania, I took everything
什么鬼
What the fuck
所有我们伪造的文件 还有重新包装子弹的照片
All the documents we forged,
photos of repacking
戴维! - 重新包装?
- David!
- Repacking?
他没告诉你吗? - 戴维!
- He didn't tell you?
- David!
对了 我们拿你投资的钱
Oh, yeah, we took that money you gave us,
买了1亿发非法中国造子弹
and we bought 100 million rounds
of illegal Chinese ammunition,
然后重新包装之后再卖给美国军队
then we repackaged it
and sold it to the US Military
但我们从中获利了8百万 混蛋
Yeah, and we made
$8 million doing it, asshole
小心点 埃佛隆
Careful, Efraim
我们报给拉尔夫的数字可只有3百万
We told Ralph we only made
$3 million on that one
等等 你说什么?
Wait, what now?
他每个月寄给你的财务报告都是伪造的
He sends you fake accounting
reports every month
噢 你去死 - 是我用笔记本合成的
- Oh, fuck off
- I make them on my laptop
你完全是在胡说八道
Now you're just making shit up
真的吗?所有的证据我都有 你个蠢驴!
Really? Because I kept everything,
you dumb fuck!
我甚至还留有我们合成并寄给政府的
I even have copies of the bank statements
that we photoshopped
银行结单的复印件
and sent to the government
别他妈说了
Get the fuck out of here
我能毁了你
I can bury you
是我们
Us
我想你要说的应该是
I think you meant to say,
你能毁了我们
you can bury us
因为所有牵扯到我的事
Because anything that implicates me,
跟你都脱不了干系
implicates you as well
埃佛隆 等等 - 不不不
- Efraim, wait
- No, no, no
我今天来本身打算付给你20万
I came here today prepared
to pay you $200,000
但现在我连早餐的钱都不会付
Now I'm not even going to pay
for breakfast
噢 现在你在干嘛呀?嗯?
Oh What's going on over here? Huh?
哪位?
Hello?
我能和戴维・佩豪斯通话吗?
May I speak with David Packouz?
我就是你是哪位? - 嗨戴维
- Yeah, who's this?
- Hi, David
我是《纽约时报》的齐福思
This is C J Chivers
withThe New York Times
想占用你几分钟时间聊聊关于AEY的事情
I was wondering if you had a minute
to talk about AEY,
还有关于非法重换中国造子弹包装的问题
and the alleged repackaging
of Chinese ammunition
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about
根据我所得到的线报现在国务院正在就此事
Well, according to my source,
there's an ongoing investigation
进行调查
at the State Department
所以我想从你这儿得到确认
And I was hoping
to get some clarification--
戴维 事情听起来挺严重的
David, this sounds pretty serious
我知道
Yeah, I know
你可以给我叔叔打电话
Maybe you should call my uncle
他是个律师
The lawyer
天啊 好的
- Oh, my God Okay
这是个好主意
That's a good idea
嘿 等我一下 我在大厅等你们
Hey, give me a minute
I'll meet you guys in the lobby
你刚刚接到《纽约时报》的电话了?
You just get a call
from The New York Times?
对
Yeah
我也是
Me too
知道吗 昨晚电视台有播《疤面煞星》
You know, Scarface was on TV last night,
我一边看一边回想起我们小时候的时光
and I was watching it and thinking about
when we were little
我们一起模仿一起说剧中台词的样子
and we used to do the lines
from the movie
你是我最好的朋友 戴维
You're my best friend, David
天啊 我真的搞砸了 不是吗?
God, I really fucked this up, didn't I?
我很抱歉 伙计
I'm sorry, bro
哇
Wow
你有不在演戏的时候吗?
Are you ever not acting, man?
你这话什么意思?
What does that mean?
你只是假装把我想听的话讲出来了而已
You just tell me
what you think I want to hear,
因为《纽约时报》的人打电话过来
because The New York Times called,
你怕我会透露什么信息给他们
and you're freaking out
that I might say something
承认吧
Just admit it
我们从来就不是好朋友
We were never best friends
你只是在扮演我的好朋友这个角色罢了
You were just playing
the part of my best friend
没错
Yeah
昨晚电视上也根本没播《疤面煞星》
Scarface wasn't even on TV last night
你真是个混蛋
You're such a piece of shit
干! - 去你妈的
- Fuck!
- Fuck you
操 - 小婊子
- Fuck
- Little bitch
这倒节省我们不少时间
Well, that saves us a trip
我们干过这么多非法的勾当
Out of all the illegal shit we did,
向政府撒过这么多谎
all the lies we told the government,
但到最后是什么把我们出卖了?
in the end, the thing that did us in?
是的 我想联系国防部
Yes, I'm trying to reach
the Department of Defense, please
埃佛隆没有付钱给为我们换盒子的人
Efraim never paid the box guy
报案应该找谁?
To who do you report a crime?
思维尔打电话给五角大楼之后
After Enver called the Pentagon,
国务院随即展开了全面的调查
the State Department launched
a full-scale investigation,
调查时间持续数月
that went on for months
他们在拉尔夫的干洗店 工作日时逮捕了他
They busted Ralph at one of his shops
in the middle of a work day
他当时害怕极了所以很快就同意协助警察调查
He was horrified
and couldn't make a deal fast enough
关于他想帮助我和埃佛隆尽早和好的屁话
All that bullshit about him wanting
to mediate a truce between Efraim and I
那都是假的
It was a setup
对了 我们还拿你投给我们的钱
Oh, yeah, we took that money you gave us,
去买了1亿发非法中国造子弹
and we bought 100 million rounds
of illegal Chinese ammunition,
然后对它进行重新包装之后再卖给美国军队
then we repackaged it
and sold it to the US Military
被他们抓了个现行
They had us dead to rights
真是悲哀啊
It was pathetic
在检查埃佛隆的电脑的时候
While going through Efraim's computer,
they even found a to-do list that said,
"重新包装中国造子弹"
"Repackage Chinese ammo"
今晚发生的故事让五角大楼为之一振
The story tonight
that has Pentagon officials scrambling
究竟两个20多数的年轻人是如何搞定国防部大合同的?
How did two 20-something young men
land a big Pentagon contract?
联邦特工于上周将两个人逮捕
Federal agents arrested
并以售卖过期
both men last week,
charging them with fraud
残次的中国造子弹给国防部的诈骗罪
for selling outdated, defective
Chinese ammunition
给其定罪
to the Pentagon
埃佛隆因触犯超过70条罪行
Efraim was charged
with over 70 federal crimes
被判入狱监禁4年
and sentenced to four years in prison
我被判有罪被罚以7个月的软禁
I pled guilty and was sentenced
to seven months house arrest
国会将此阿富汗合同一案
Congress called the Afghanistan contract
a case study
作为政府正确采购过程的反面教材
in all that is wrong
with the government's procurement process
AEY要到2022年 才能再次投标联邦合同
In 2022, AEY will be eligible once again
to bid on Federal contracts
过得怎么样?
How's it going?
还行
It's okay
如果我真想要你的命 你早就死了
If I wanted you dead,
you'd already be dead
现在没什么问题了
I guess it's going all right then
请进
Come in
你孩子还好吗?
How's your baby?
是个女儿 对吧?
It's a girl, right?
对 她很好
Yeah She's good
我有3个孩子
I got three
都是女儿
All girls
大家都说她们长大之后情况会好起来
They tell you it gets better
但这并不是真的情况 只会越来越糟
That's not true, it gets worse
所以我才这么喜欢跟军火打交道
That's why I like the arms business
因为干这一行的没有女人
No women
我想就阿尔巴尼亚的事表示抱歉
I want to apologize about Albania
我收到的情报不太准确
I had bad information
所以你把我塞进汽车后备箱 用枪指着我的头 只是个失误?
So you stuffed me in the trunk of a car
and shoved a gun in my face by mistake?
是的
Yeah
我不是个坏人 但在某些情况下
I'm not a bad man,
but in certain situations,
我会自问
I have to ask myself,
如果是坏人 他会怎么做?
what would a bad man do?
我很感谢你在接受调查的时候没有供出我
I appreciate you leaving my name
out of your testimony
我觉得没这个必要
I didn't really see
a reason to include it
但还是谢谢你
Yeah, but still
我能问你个问题吗?
Can I ask you a question?
当然
Sure
我们在维加斯的21点牌桌上遇见
When we met in Vegas
at the blackjack table,
真的是巧合吗?
was that a coincidence?
你觉得呢?
What do you think?
我能再问一个问题吗?
Can I ask you another question?
我在阿尔巴尼亚的司机失踪了
My driver in Albania went missing
你知道他出什么事了吗?
Do you know what happened to him?
这是我在"阿富汗问题"上赚到的最后一笔钱
It's a piece of my end on the Afghan deal
都是给你的
It's for you
不要再问问题了
No more questions